快过来
Hey! Come here!
马上就来
I'm on my way.
他已经神志不清了 但还是指名要见你
把他带进来
他身上只带了这个...
还有这个
你是来杀我的吗
Are you here to kill me?
我知道这是什么
I know what this is.
很久很久以前
I've seen one before.
我就见过这个
Many,many years ago.
记得我做过一个梦
}It belonged to a man I met
那个模糊的梦里就有这东西
in a half-remembered dream.
那个人满脑子都是些疯狂的念头
A man possessed of some radical notions.
寄生你体内的什么东西最顽强
What is the most resilient parasite?
细菌 病毒
A bacteria? A virus?
还是蛔虫
An intestinal worm?
Cobb先生的意思是说...
Uh...What Mr. Cobb is trying to say
一个想法
An idea.
顽强无比 感染性极强
Resilient. Highly contagious.
一旦有一个想法占据了你的大脑
Once an idea has taken hold of the brain,
那就很难再去摆脱它了
it's almost impossible to eradicate.
经过充分思考 理解消化
An idea that is fully formed,fully understood,
当这个想法完全成型以后
that sticks.
就会永远根植在那里
Right in there somewhere.
然后你们就可以偷走它
For someone like you to steal?
是的 你做梦的时候 你的防备意识也沉睡了
Yes. In the dream state,your conscious defenses are lowered...
如此一来你的想法很容易被偷走
and that makes your thoughts vulnerable to theft.
这就叫做盗梦
It's called extraction.
斋藤先生 我们完全可以训练你的潜意识进行自我防御
Mr. Saito,we can train your subconscious to defend itself...
就算最出色的盗梦者也无计可施
from even the most skilled extractor.
你凭什么能做到
How can you do that?
因为我就是最出色的盗梦者
Because I am the most skilled extractor.
我能窥探你的想法 找出你大脑里的所有秘密
I know how to search your mind and find your secrets.
我精通其中窍门
I know the tricks.
我可以教你 这样即使睡着了
And I can teach them to you,so that even when you're asleep...
你的潜意识也不会放松警惕
your defense is never down.
如果 想让我教你
Look,if you want my help,
就得完全信任我 对我毫无保留
you're gonna have to be completely open with me.
我得比你的妻子、心里医生
I need to know my way around your thoughts better than your wife...
比任何人 都更了解你的想法
better than your therapist,better than anyone.
比如你的梦里有个装满秘密的保险箱
If this is a dream,and you have a safe full of secrets...
我必须知道里面是什么
I need to know what's in that safe.
为了达到效果 你的大脑必须完全对我开放
In order for this all to work,you need to completely let me in.
两位请慢用
Enjoy your evening,gentlemen,
我会考虑看看的
as I consider your proposal.
他知道了
He knows.
上面一层怎么了
What's going on up there?
斋藤都知道了 他在耍我们
Saito knows. He's playing with us.
别担心 我会搞定 相信我
Doesn't matter. I can get it here. Trust me.
情报就在保险箱里
The information is in the safe.
我提到秘密的时候 他就盯着保险箱看
He looked right at it when I mentioned secrets.
她怎么来了
What's she doing here?
你先回房 剩下的就交给我了
Just head back to the room. All right? I'll take care of this.
别忘了 我们是来做正事的
Okay,make sure you do. We're here to work.
从这跳下去 还能活得了吗
If I jumped,would I survive?
运气好的话还行
With a clean dive,perhaps.
Mal 你来这干嘛
Mal,what are you doing here?
我以为你会想我的
I thought you might be missing me.
我当然想你
You know that I am.
不过我再也不敢相信你了
But I can't trust you anymore.
所以呢
So what?
一看就像是Arthur的品味
Looks like Arthur's taste.
我们这次的目标对战后的英国画家很感兴趣
Actually,the subject is partial to postwar British painters.
请坐吧
Please,have a seat.
跟我说说
Tell me...
孩子们有没有想我
do the children miss me?
想的要命
You can't imagine.
你要干什么
What are you doing?
出去透透气
Just getting some fresh air.
你坐那别动  Mal
Stay where you are,Mal.
天 该死
God,damn it.
转过身来
Turn around.
Dom 把枪放下
The gun,Dom.
快点
Please.
那个信封 物归原主吧  Cobb先生
Now the envelope,Mr. Cobb.
她告诉你的 还是你早就知道了
Did she tell you? Or have you known all along?
知道你是是个小偷 还是 知道我们其实在梦里
That you're here to steal from me,or that we are actually asleep?
我想知道是谁雇你们来的
I want to know the name of your employer.
在梦里你拿个枪威胁他 有什么用  Mal
Ah,there's no use threatening him in a dream,right,Mal?
那得看你怎么威胁了
That depends on what you're threatening.
杀了他只会让他醒过来
Killing him would just wake him up.
不过呢 疼痛...
But pain...
他大脑会感受到疼痛
Pain is in the mind.
从场景布局来看（前面提到英国画像是Arthur喜欢的）
And judging by the decor,
我们是在你的梦里吧 Arthur
we're in your mind,aren't we,Arthur?
搞什么 你醒得太早了
What are you doing? It's too soon.
我知道 梦境已经崩溃
I know. But the dream's collapsing.
我要想办法让斋藤多在那多呆一会（指加催眠剂 不让他醒来）
I'm gonna try to keep Saito under a little bit longer.
就快得手了
We're almost there.
好险 他差点就得手了
He was close. Very close.
拦住他
Stop him!
没戏了 把他叫醒
This isn't gonna work. Wake him up.
叫不醒啊
He won't wake.
机密
-让他穿越 -什么
- Give him the kick. - What?
把他推水里
Dunk him.
他昏过去了
He's out.
你是有备而来啊
You came prepared,hmm?
连我的高级保镖都不知道这
Not even my head of security knows this apartment.
你怎么找着的
How did you find it?
像你这种地位的男人
It's difficult for a man of your position
想金屋藏娇 可不容易啊
to keep a love nest like this secret...
尤其你的情妇还是有夫之妇
particularly where there's a married woman involved.
-不可能  -但事实摆着 我们就在这了
- She would never... - Yet here we are.
-进退两难啊  -他们慢慢逼近了
- With a dilemma. - They're getting closer.
}-你拿到了你想要的  -还没有
- You got what you came for. - Well,that's not true.
你把文件上的关键部分全划掉了
You left out a key piece of information,didn't you?
你有所保留是因为你知道我们是来干什么的
You held something back because you knew what we were up to.
-但你为何还让我们进来  -算是一次面试
- Question is,why'd you let us in at all? - An audition.
-面试什么  -不重要了 你失败了
- An audition for what? - Doesn't matter. You failed.
我们把你脑袋里的信息偷出来了
We extracted every bit of information you had in there.
可你们的花招被我看穿了
But your deception was obvious.
好了 你们走吧
So leave me and go.
你没有搞清楚状况 斋藤先生
You don't seem to understand,Mr. Saito.
雇佣我们的公司  是可不允许我们失手的
That corporation that hired us,they won't accept failure.
我们活不过两天
We won't last two days.
Cobb
Cobb?
看来我只能使用原始手段了
Looks like I'm gonna have to do this a little more simply.
把你知道的告诉我们
Tell us what you know!
把知道的告诉我们 快
Tell us what you know,now!
我一直很讨厌这里的地毯
I've always hated this carpet.
因为它又旧又脏 连褪个色都与众不同
It's stained and frayed in such distinctive ways.
不过好歹它是条羊毛毯子
But very definitely made of wool.
可这条...
Right now...
却是是涤纶的（人造纤维）
I'm lying on polyester.
也就是说 我现在根本没有趴在自己公寓的地毯上
Which means I'm not lying on my carpet,in my apartment.
你果然名不虚传 Cobb先生
You have lived up to your reputation,Mr. Cobb.
我现在依然在梦里
I'm still dreaming.
-进展如何  -不太妙
- How'd it go? - Not good.
梦中有梦 非常精彩
Dream within a dream,huh? I'm impressed.
但在我梦里 得由我说了算
But in my dream,you play by my rules.
这么说吧 斋藤先生...
Ah,yes,but you see,Mr. Saito...
我们不是在你的梦里
We're not in your dream.
而是在我的梦里
We're in mine.
你二啊 怎么会把地毯搞错的
Asshole. How do you mess up the carpet?
-这不能怪我  -你可是筑梦师
- It wasn't my fault. - You're the architect.
又不是我把他揍到地上的
I didn't know he was gonna rub his cheek on it!
好了 够了
That's enough.
还有你 你是怎么回事
You. What the hell was all that?
-我控制住了局势  -你这就叫控制了
- I have it under control. - I'd hate to see you out of control.
没时间争论了 我要在京都下车
We don't have time for this. I'm getting off at Kyoto.
干嘛啊 他又不会检查每一节车厢
Why? He's not gonna check every compartment.
没错 但我不喜欢坐火车（原因在后面）
Yeah,well,I don't like trains.
都听好 大家自求多福
Listen. Every man for himself.
喂 你好
Yes,hello?
-爸爸  -爸爸
- Hi,Daddy. - Hi,Dad.
Hey 小家伙们 你们好吗 过得怎样
Hey,guys. Hey. How are you? How you doing,huh?
-很好  -还行
- Good. - Okay,I guess.
还行 是谁说还行 是James吗
Okay? Who's just okay? Is that you,James?
嗯 是我 爸爸 你什么时候回家
Yeah. When are you coming home,Dad?
现在还不行 亲爱的
Well,I can't,sweetheart. I can't.
还需要一段时间
Not for a while,remember?
为什么
Why?
我不是跟你们说过了吗  我在外面工作
Look,I told you,I'm away because I'm working,right?
外婆说你再也不会回来了
Grandma says you're never coming back.
是Phillipa吗
Phillipa,is that you?
让外婆听电话好吗
Put Grandma on the phone for me,will you?
她在摇头
She's shaking her head.
那个 外婆说的不对
Well,just hope she's wrong about that.
爸爸
Daddy?
James怎么了
Yeah,James?
妈妈跟你在一起吗
Is Mommy with you?
James 我跟你说过了
James,we talked about this.
妈妈她已经不在了
Mommy's not here anymore.
她去哪了
Where?
好了 孩子们 说再见吧
That's enough,kids. Say bye-bye.
喂 我会让外公帮我给你们礼物回去
Listen,I'm gonna send some presents with Grandpa,all right?
你们要乖啊...
And you be good,you be...
-直升机来了 屋顶  -好
- Our ride's on the roof. - Right.
你没事吧
Hey,are you okay?
当然 怎么了
Yeah. Yeah,I'm fine. Why?
在梦里时  Mal出现了
Well,down in the dream,Mal showing up.
噢 很抱歉 她开枪打了你的腿
Look,I'm,uh,sorry about your leg.
下不为例
Won't happen again.
情况越来越糟了吧
It's getting worse,isn't it?
Arthur 我除了抱歉 没有其他解释
One apology's all you're getting,all right,Arthur?
-Nash他人呢  -他还没来 要等他吗
- Where's Nash? - He hasn't shown. You wanna wait?
我们在2小时前就该把
We were supposed to deliver Saito's expansion plans...
斋藤的扩建方案送给Cobol公司
to Cobol Engineering two hours ago
他们肯定知道我们搞砸了
By now,they know we failed.
是时候闪人了
It's time we disappear.
-你要去哪   -布宜诺斯艾利斯
- Where you gonna go? - Buenos Aires.
先避一避风头
I can lie low there,
等风声平息候再揽个活干 你呢
maybe sniff out a job when things quiet down. You?
回美国
Stateside.
向家里人问好
Send my regards.
他出卖了你们 跑来求我饶他一命
He sold you out. Thought to come to me and bargain for his life.
好了 还是你们自己来处理吧
So I offer you the satisfaction.
这不是我的风格
It's not the way I deal with things.
-你要怎么处置他  -不管他
- What will you do with him? - Nothing.
不过Cobol公司会如何处理 那就难说了
But I can't speak for Cobol Engineering.
-你想让我们干什么  -植入想法
- What do you want from us? - Inception.
-可能吗  -当然不可能
- Is it possible? - Of course not.
既然能从别人脑子里偷走想法
If you can steal an idea from someone's mind...
为什么不能反过来植入一个想法
why can't you plant one there instead?
好 我来给你植入一个想法
Okay,here's me planting an idea in your head.
我对你说 "别去想大象"
I say,"Don't think about elephants".
你会想什么
What are you thinking about?
大象
Elephants.
没错 因为这是我强加给你的想法
Right. But it's not your idea,
我越是不让你去想什么 你反而越是会去想
Because you know I gave it to you.
人总能发现想法的来源
The subject's mind can always trace the genesis of the idea.
-真正的动机是无法作假的  -不能那么说
- True inspiration's impossible to fake. - That's not true.
-你能做到吗  -你想帮我们躲避追杀？
- Can you do it? - Are you offering me a choice?
我自己就能把Cobol公司搞定
Because I can find my own way to square things with Cobol.
看来你不需要我这个选择
Then you do have a choice.
我只想选择离开着
Then I choose to leave,sir.
告诉飞行员你们要去哪儿
Tell the crew where you want to go.
Hey Cobb先生
Hey,Mr. Cobb.
让你回家意下如何 回到美国 和孩子们团圆
How would you like to go home,to America,to your children?
这太难 你做不到 没人能做到
You can't fix that. No one can.
-比植如想法还难吗  -走啦 Cobb
- Just like inception. - Cobb,come on.
-你要植入的想法有多复杂  -其实 相当简单
- How complex is the idea? - Simple enough.
任何你要植入别人大脑的想法
No idea is simple when you need to plant it
都不可能简单
in somebody else's mind.
我最大的竞争对手是个病入膏肓的老人
My main competitor is an old man in poor health.
他的儿子马上就要接管他的公司
His son will soon inherit control of the corporation.
我想要他毁掉他父亲创建的帝国
I need him to decide to break up his father's empire.
-Cobb 我们不要趟这摊浑水  -先等一下
- Cobb,we should walk away from this. - Hold on.
如果我愿意干 我是说 如果我确实做到了
If I were to do this,if I even could do it...
你必须给我一个承诺
I'd need a guarantee.
-不然我凭什么相信你会帮我回家  -你别无选择
- How do I know you can deliver? - You don't.
但我可以做到
But I can.
你愿意放手一搏
So do you want to take a leap of faith...
还是要等到年华逝去 在悔恨中度过余生
or become an old man,filled with regret...
孤零零地等死
waiting to die alone?
组建你的团队吧  Cobb先生
Assemble your team,Mr. Cobb.
这次可别再选错人了
And choose your people more wisely.
我知道你有多想回家
Look,I know how much you wanna go home.
但这活我们干不了
This can't be done.
干得了
Yes,it can.
只要潜入得足够深
Just have to go deep enough.
你怎么知道
You don't know that.
我以前做过
I've done it before.
对谁植入的
Who'd you do it to?
为什么去巴黎
Why are we going to Paris?
找个新的筑梦师
We're gonna need a new architect.
你就从来没喜欢过你的办公室 是吧
You never did like your office,did you?
那地方小得就像个壁橱 根本没法思考
No space to think in that broom cupboard.
你来这里安全吗
Is it safe for you to be here?
你也知道 法国和美国间的引渡条款
Extradition between France and the United States...
乱得像团麻
is a bureaucratic nightmare,you know that.
说不定就你的案子
I think they might find a way
为了抓你 他们会想办法破个例
to make it work in your case.
如果...方便的话
Look,I,uh,brought these for you to...
帮我把礼物带给孩子
give to the kids when you have a chance.
你想让他们感觉还有个父亲
It'll take more than the occasional stuffed animal...
偶尔送些小礼物可不够啊
to convince those children they still have a father.
我只是尽我所能
I'm just doing what I know.
这些都是你教我的
I'm doing what you taught me.
我可没教你去当小偷
I never taught you to be a thief.
没 你教我如何操纵别人的思想
No,you taught me to navigate people's minds.
但那次出事以后...
But after what happened...
我再也没有机会
there weren't a whole lot of legitimate ways
合法地施展这个能力了
for me to use that skill.
Dom 你来这想干嘛
What are you doing here,Dom?
我找到了回家的办法
I think I found a way home.
帮一个非常有权势的人干一票
It's a job for some very,very powerful people.
他就能彻底撤销对那些对我莫须有的指控
People who I believe can fix my charges permanently.
但我要你帮点忙
But I need your help.
你是来骗走我最好最聪明的学生吗
You're here to corrupt one of my brightest and best.
你知道我开的条件优越
You know what I'm offering.
你得让他们自己决定
Let them decide for themselves.
-钱吗  -不仅仅是钱
- Money. - Not just money.
你应该知道
You remember.
这是一个千载难逢的机会
It's the chance to
你可以去去建造教堂 去造城市
build cathedrals,entire cities...
去造现实世界从未存在的
things that never existed...
也绝不可能存在的事物
things that couldn't exist in the real world.
你是想找我的一个学生
So you want me to let someone else
跟你一起进入梦幻世界？
follow you into your fantasy?
他们不必亲自进入梦境
They don't actually come into the dream.
他们只需要替盗梦者
They just design the levels
设计梦境的每一个场景就行了
and teach them to the dreamers. That's all.
你自己设计吧
Design it yourself.
Mal会阻止我的
Mal won't let me.
回到现实中来吧  Dom
Come back to reality,Dom.
-求你了  -现实
- Please. - Reality.
我的孩子们 也就是你的外孙们...
Those kids,your grandchildren...
正在苦苦等着他们的爸爸回家
they're waiting for their father to come back home.
这个就是他们的现实
That's their reality.
而只有干完这最后一票
And this job,this last job,
我才能实现这个愿望 才可以回家
that's how I get there.
我要不是走投无路  我绝不会来这求你的
I would not be standing here if I knew any other way.
我需要个和我一样出色的筑梦师
I need an architect who's as good as I was.
有个比你更出色的
I've got somebody better.
Ariadne
Ariadne?
介绍一下 Cobb先生
I'd like you to meet Mr. Cobb.
幸会
Pleased to meet you.
如果你有空
If you have a few moments,
Cobb先生这儿有份工作
Mr. Cobb has a job offer.
不知道你感不感兴趣
He'd like to discuss with you.
是实习吗
A work placement?
不算吧
Not exactly.
先来做个测试吧
I have a test for you.
先跟我说说是什么样的工作
You're not gonna tell me anything first?
我想先看看你能否胜任这个工作
Before I describe the job,I have to know you can do it.
-为什么  -严格来说 这份工作并不合法
- Why? - It's not,strictly speaking,legal.
我给你两分钟 来设计一个
You have two minutes to design a maze
不能在一分钟之内破解的迷宫
that it takes one minute to solve.
停
Stop.
再来
Again.
停
Stop.
还是太简单了
You're gonna have to do better than that.
这才像话
That's more like it.
有人说我们醒着的时候
They say we only use a fraction of our brain's true potential.
大脑隐藏了大部分的潜能
Now,that's when we're awake.
而睡着的时候 大脑却几乎无所不能
When we're asleep,our mind can do almost anything.
比如呢
Such as?
比如说 你正在设计一幢楼房
Imagine you're designing a building.
你必须有意识地设计每一个细节
You consciously create each aspect.
但有时候 楼房像在自己设计自己
But sometimes,it feels like it's almost creating itself,
明白吗
if you know what I mean.
明白 好像我只是发现了它
Yeah,like I'm discovering it.
这就叫灵感 对吗
Genuine inspiration,right?
可做梦的时候
Now,in a dream,our mind continuously does this.
我们一边设计 一边发现这个世界 创造和感知同步发生
We create and perceive our world simultaneously.
这一切非常自然
And our mind does this so well
自然到我们都感觉不到
that we don't even know it's happening.
所以我们可以直接侵入这个过程
That allows us to get right in the middle of that process.
-怎么做  -接管大脑的设计工作
- How? - By taking over the creating part.
而这就是你的工作
Now,this is where I need you.
我需要你创造一个 梦境
You create the world of the dream.
然后把目标带进来
We bring the subject into that dream,
接下来 目标的潜意识 会产生梦境里的居民
and they fill it with their subconscious.
我要设计得多细致
How could I ever acquire enough detail
才能让目标相信他们身在现实 没在做梦
to make them think that it's reality?
其实呢 我们做梦的时候都感觉很真实
Well,dreams,they feel real while we're in them,right?
只有等我们醒来的时候
It's only when we wake up
才会意识到有些事情不大对劲
that we realize something was actually strange.
那我问你
Let me ask you a question.
你是不是从不记得梦的开始
You never really remember the beginning of a dream,do you?
而记住的 都是中间的一些过程
You always wind up right in the middle of what's going on.
好像是的
I guess,yeah.
那我们是怎么来这的
So how did we end up here?
我们刚从...
Well,we just came from the,uh...
仔细想 Ariadne 你怎么来这的
Think about it,Ariadne. How did you get here?
你现在到底在哪儿
Where are you right now?
在做梦？
We're dreaming?
你正正睡觉 同时也在上课
You're in the middle of the workshop,sleeping.
这是你学习分享梦境的第一课 冷静点
This is your first lesson in shared dreaming. Stay calm.
要是在做梦的话 你干嘛要保护...
If it's just a dream,then why are you covering...
因为这梦永远不只是梦
Because it's never just a dream,is it?
玻璃刺在脸上 会非常疼
And a face full of glass hurts like hell.
做梦的时候 感觉都是真实的
When you're in it,it feels real.
所以军队开发了梦境分享系统
That's why the military developed dream sharing.
士兵可以在里面相互射击
It was a training program for soldiers to shoot,
格斗和搏杀等等
stab and strangle each other...
然后再醒过来 不会真的受伤
and then wake up.
筑梦师的工作是什么
How did architects become involved?
总得有人来设计梦境吧
Well,someone had to design the dreams,right?
干嘛不再给我们五分钟
Why don't you give us another five minutes?
五分钟？
Five minutes?
怎么会 我们少说也聊了一个小时
What? We were talking for,like,at least an hour.
做梦时 大脑的运转速度非常快
In a dream,your mind functions more quickly...
所以感觉时间过得比较慢
therefore time seems to feel more slow.
现实世界的五分钟 相当于梦境里的一小时
Five minutes in the real world gives you an hour in the dream.
试试看你在五分钟内能做设计出什么来
Why don't you see what you can get up to in five minutes?
基本布局你已经有了 书店 咖啡店
You've got the basic layout. Bookstore,cafe?
其他该有的也都有了
Almost everything else is here too.
-那他们是谁  -我潜意识产生的防御者
- Who are the people? - Projections of my subconscious.
-你的潜意识  -对
- Yours? - Yes.
记住 你是做梦者 你设计梦境
Remember,you are the dreamer. You build this world.
而我是你的目标 这些人是我大脑产生的
I am the subject. My mind populates it.
你可以和目标的潜意识直接对话
You can literally talk to my subconscious.
这也是偷取信息的一种办法
That's one of the ways we extract information from the subject.
除此之外呢
How else do you do it?
你可以设计一个安全场所
By creating something secure,
比如银行金库 或是监狱
like a bank vault or a jail.
重要信息就会自动存入其中
The mind automatically fills it with information it's trying to protect.
懂了吗
You understand?
-然后你就会潜入梦境去偷  -这个嘛...
- Then you break in and steal it? - Well...
我一直以为梦是视觉来构建的
I guess I thought that the dream's space should be all about the visual,
但其实其他感觉好像更重要
but it's more about the feel of it.
我想知道 如果我颠覆了
My question is what happens when you
物理规律 会怎样
start messing with the physics of it all?
-很厉害吧  -是啊
- It's something,isn't it? - Yes,it is.
他们为什么都看着我
Why are they all looking at me?
因为我的潜意识怀疑这不是一个真实的世界
Because my subconscious feels that someone else is creating this world.
你改变的东西越多
The more you change things,
防御者们就会越快地涌向你
the quicker the projections start to converge on you.
涌向我？
Converge?
他们能感觉到你是个入侵者
They sensed the foreign nature of the dreamer.
就会像血液里的白细胞会攻击细菌一样
They attack like white blood cells fighting an infection.
他们会攻击我们
Are they gonna attack us?
错 只攻击你
No,actually,just you.
这样的设计是很棒
This is great. But I'm telling you,
但如果你再这么继续下去...
if you keep changing things like this...
受不了 就不能让你的潜意识冷静点么
Gees! Mind telling your subconscious to take it easy?
这可是我的潜意识 我自己没法控制
It's my subconscious,remember,I can't control it.
佩服
Very impressive.
这座桥我见过 它是现实中的 对吗
I know this bridge. This place is real,isn't it?
是啊 我每天上学都会经过这
Yeah,I cross it everyday to get to the college.
绝对不能根据记忆重建场景
Never recreate places from your memory,
必须创造新的东西
always imagine new places.
那总会借用熟悉的东西吧
Well,you gotta draft from stuff you know,right?
只能借用细节...
Only use details,uh...
比如路灯啊电话亭啊  但绝不能复制整块地区
A street lamp,or a phone booth,never entire areas.
为什么
Why not?
当你凭记忆构建梦境的时候
Because building a dream from your memory...
极易让你迷失 何为梦境何为现实
is the easiest way to lose your grasp on  what's real and what is a dream.
-看来你搞混过  -喂
- Is that what happened to you? - Listen to me,
这和我无关 懂吗
this has nothing to do with me,understand?
所以你才需要我来帮你筑梦
Is that why you need me to build your dreams?
别碰她 走开
Get off of her. Back off.
-滚开  -别碰我
- Back off! - No!
别碰她
Get off of her!
Mal
Mal!
把我叫醒  快把我叫醒
Wake me up! Wake me up!
Mal Mal
Mal! Mal!
叫醒我
Wake me up! Wake me up!
看着我 你没事了 没事了
Hey,hey,hey! Look at me. You're okey? You're okey?
为什么我醒不过来
Why... why wouldn't I wake up?
因为时间没到 所以你醒不了
Because there was still some time on the clock,
除非你在死在梦里 不然没法提前醒来
and you can't wake up within a dream unless you die.
-她需要个图腾  -什么
- She'll need a totem. - What?
图腾是个小的私人物品...
A totem is a small personal...
你的防御者可真厉害啊  Cobb
That's some subconscious you've got in you,Cobb.
还是个大美人呢
She's a real charmer!
看来你见过Cobb夫人了
Oh,I see you met Mrs. Cobb.
-那是他妻子？  -对 话说图腾...
- She's his wife? - Yeah. So... a totem,
就是一个有分量的小物件
you need a small object potentially heavy,
你可以一直带在身边
something could have on you all the time
-但不能让别人知道  -硬币行吗
- that no one else knows. - Like a coin?
不行 必须更独特些才行
No,it must be more unique than that.
比如这个注铅的骰子
This is a loaded die.
你不能碰 碰了就没用了
No,I can't let you touch it,that would defeat the purpose.
只有我知道这个特制骰子的重心在哪里
Only I know the balance and the weight of this particular loaded die.
只有这样 当你看到自己的图腾
That way,when you look at your totem,
你才能确信自己不在别人的梦里
you know,beyond a doubt,that you're not in someone else's dream.
我 我问你啊...
I... I don't know...
你是看不出来 还是不想看出来发生了什么
if you can't see what's going on,or if you just don't want to,
Cobb的心里问题很严重 而且他还想把那些问题藏起来
but Cobb has some serious problems that he's tried to bury down there.
我绝对不会允许这样的人进入我的梦境
And I'm not about to just open my mind to someone like that.
她会回来的
She'll be back.
我还从没见过有人学得这么快
I've never seen anyone pick it up that quickly before.
现实已经满足不了她了
Reality is not gonna be enough for her now.
等她回来...
When she comes back...
你可以开始教她设计迷宫了
when she comes back,you're gonna help her building mazes.
-那你呢  -我要去找Eames
- Where're you gonna be? - I gotta go visit Eames.
Eames 他不是在蒙巴萨吗[肯尼亚港口城市]
Eames? Now he's in Mombasa.
那里可是Cobol公司的老巢
It's Cobol's backyard.
必须冒这个险
It's a necessary risk.
神偷多了去了
There's plenty of good thieves.
可好的伪装者不多 他最合适
We don't just need a thief. We need a forger.
你再怎么搓它们也下不出崽儿来
You can rub them together all you want,they're not gonna breed.
这不好说啊
You never know.
过来喝一杯
I'll get you a drink.
好 你请
You're buying.
（他明明在赌桌上输掉所有筹码）
（可还有筹码换钱）
-你的拼写没什么长进啊（意指其伪造） -给我滚
- Your spelling hasn't improved. - Piss off.
-会模仿笔迹吗  -必须 我这么多才多艺
- How's your handwriting? - Versatile.
-那就好  -谢了
- Good. - Thank you very much.
植入想法
Inception.
你先别和我说这办不到 不可能...
Now,before you bother telling me it's impossible...
非常可能 就是难得要死
No,it's perfectly possible. It's just bloody difficult.
只是难吗
Just difficult?
Arthur总说这是不可能的
Arthur keeps telling me it can't be done.
哈 Arthur 还和那个木头脑袋在一起
Hmm... Arthur. You're still working with that stick-in-the-mud?
他有他的特长
He's good at what he does,right?
是不错 只是缺乏想象力
Oh,the best. He has no imagination.
-不像你  -真的 如果你要植入一个想法的话
- Not like you. - Listen,if you wanna perform inception,
-就必须要有想象力  -那好我问你
- you need imagination. - Let me ask you something,
-你以前做过吗  -我们试过
- have you done it before? - We tried it.
把想法放进去了 但没有巩固住
We got the idea in place,but it didn't take.
因为植入得不够深
You didn't plant it deep enough?
这不仅仅是深度的问题
It's not just about depth,you know...
要把想法简化到最简形式再植入
you need the simplest version of the idea,
这样才能在主体大脑中自然成长
in order it to grow naturally in the subject's mind.
这是相当精妙的技艺
That's a very subtle art.
来 说下你要植入的想法是什么
So what is this idea that you need to plant?
我们要让一个大公司的继承人
We need the heir of a major corporation
瓦解他父亲的能源帝国
to dissolve his father's empire.
你看 你可以从各种政治动机的角度来考虑...
Well,you see right there,you have various political motivations of...
比如 反垄断的情绪等诸如此类的
anti-monopolistic sentiments and so forth,and all of that stuff.
能不能植入
That's all.
关键得看目标人物的那个心结有多大 懂吗
It's really at the mercy of your subject's prejudice,you see?
你必须从一个最根本的问题入手
All you have to do is to start with the absolute basic.
-你指的是  -他和父亲之间的关系
- Which is what? - The relationship with the father.
-找到药剂师了吗  -还没有
- Do you have a chemist? - No,not yet.
那好
Alright.
我这倒有个人选 叫Yusuf Pierro
Okey,there's a man here,Yusuf Pierro.
他的催眠剂配方独一无二
He formulates his own versions of the compounds.
什么时候带我去见见
When are you taking me there?
你先甩掉跟踪你的人吧
Once you've lost your tail.
吧台边儿上那个
Man at the bar.
Cobol 公司开的赏金
Cobol engineering.
是要活捉我还是要杀了我
That price on my head,was that "dead or alive?"
不记得了 看他开不开枪
I don't remember. Let's see if he starts shooting.
替我引开他 然后过半个小时
Run interference,I'll meet you downstairs in the bar in,say uh...
楼下门口碰头
say half an hour?
-还回来  -最危险的地方最安全
- Be back here? - It's the last place they'd expect.
哈 好
Hum-hmm. Well...
Freddy  Freddy Savens
Freddy,Freddy Savens?
天啊 还真是你啊
My God,it's you,isn't it?
看来我认错人了
No,it isn't.
这下你不是在做梦了吧
You're not dreaming now,are you?
那边
There!
没事
Okey.
咖啡 要一杯咖啡
Oh,uh... cafe. One... one cafe.
一杯咖啡
One cafe.
要搭车么 伙计
Care for a lift,Mr. Cobb?
你来蒙巴萨干嘛
What're you doing here in Mombasa?
来保护我的投资对象
I need to protect my investments.
你就是这么甩掉冤家的啊
Ahh,so this is your idea of losing a tail,uh?
另一个冤家这是
Different tail.
Cobb说了你会回来
Cobb said you'd be back.
我也不想 可我...
I tried not to come. But...
已经无法自拔了
But there's nothing quite like it.
我只喜欢...纯粹的创造
It's just... pure creation.
我们先来学一下不可能建筑吧
Shall we take a look at some paradoxical architecture?
想要构建完整的三层梦境
You're gonna have to master a few tricks,
有些窍门你必须要掌握
if you're gonna build three complete dream levels.
不好意思 让一下
Excuse me.
什么窍门
What kind of tricks?
在梦里 你可以把建筑设计成不可能的图形
In a dream,you can cheat architecture into impossible shapes.
这样你就能造出闭合的路线
That lets you create closed loops,
比如著名的 没有尽头的 彭罗斯阶梯
like the Penrose steps,the infinite staircases.
看见没
See?
矛盾建筑
Paradox.
这样的闭合路线
So a closed loop like that will help you
可以帮你隐藏梦境的边界
disguise the boundaries of the dream you create.
我需要设计多大的场景
But how big do these levels have to be?
随你 可以是一层楼 也可以是整座城市
It could be anything from the floor of a building to an entire city.
但梦境场景结构必须够复杂
But they have to be complicated
好让我们有藏身之处 躲避防御者的追踪
enough that we can hide from the projections.
比如一个迷宫
A maze?
对 迷宫 迷宫越复杂...
Right,a maze,and the better the maze...
防御者就越难找到我们
Then the longer we have before the projections catch us?
-没错  -看来我潜意识里的防御者就很有礼貌
- Exactly. - My subconscious seems polite enough.
等着瞧 他们会翻脸不认人的
You wait,they'll turn ugly.
没人喜欢别人在自己的大脑里乱来的
No one likes to feel someone else messing around in their mind.
Cobb已经不能再筑梦了吗
Cobb can't build anymore,can he?
就算他可以 他也不愿意
I don't know if he can't,but he won't.
他说他不熟悉设计会更安全
He thinks it's safer if he doesn't know the layouts.
为什么
Why?
他不愿意说  我想是因为Mal吧
He won't tell me. I think it's Mal.
-他的前妻？  -不 不是前妻
- His ex-wife? - No,not his ex.
-他们还在一起  -没有  她...
- They're still together? - No,she...
她已经去世了
she's dead.
你看到的只是他潜意识里的Mal
What you just see in there is just his projection of her.
-她在现实中什么样  -很迷人
- What was she like in real life? - She was lovely.
-你要找药剂师  -对
- You're seeking a chemist? - Yes.
是要调配催眠剂吗
To formulate compounds for a job.
还要和我们一起进入梦境 工作
And to go into the field with us.
我很少进入梦境  Cobb先生
No,I rarely go into the field,Mr. Cobb.
你得一直跟着我们 根据需要 在梦里调配药剂
We need you there to tailor compounds specific to our needs.
-有什么要求  -足够深度
- Which are? - Great depth.
梦中梦吗 两层梦境
A dream within a dream? two levels?
-三层  -这不可能
- Three. - Not possible.
这种多层梦境太不稳定了
That many dreams within dreams is too unstable.
有可能 只需要在配方里增加加镇静剂
It is possible. You just have to add a sedative.
超级无敌强效镇静剂
A powerful sedative.
-一共几个人  -五个
- How many team members? - Five.
六个
Six.
为了确定你是否完成任务
The only way to know you've done the job
我得跟你一起进去
is if I go in with you.
这种工作带游客 可不行啊
There's no room for tourists on a job like this,
斋藤先生
Mr. Saito.
那这次得破例了
This time it seems there is.
我们可以用这个作为基础 我每天都用
This,I think,is a good place to start. I use it everyday.
-用来做什么  -来 我带你看看
- What for? - Here,I'll show you.
-做好心理准备  -你先请
- Perhaps,you will not want to see. - After you.
十个...十二个 全部连在一起
Ten... twelve,all connected.
我 的 妈 呀
Bloody hell!
他们每天来这分享梦境
They come here everyday to share the dream.
看见没 非常稳定
You see? Very stable.
-他们每天做梦多久  -三四个小时吧
- How long do they dream for? - Three,four hours,each day.
-梦里是多久  -在这种药效下
- And the dream time? - With this compound?
每人每天四十个小时
About 40 hours,each and every day.
他们为什么这么做
Why do they do it?
你来说吧 Cobb先生
Tell him,Mr. Cobb.
在你用药一阵子后
After a while,
不用药就没法做梦了
it becomes the only way you can dream.
你还做梦吗 Cobb先生
Do you still dream,Mr. Cobb?
他们每天来这做梦吗
They come here everyday to sleep?
不 他们来这是为了醒过来
No,they come to be woken up.
梦境已成了他们的现实世界 谁说现实不是梦境呢
The dream has become their reality. Who are you to say otherwise,uh?
让我见识一下吧
Let's see what you can do.
你知道怎么找到我 你知道你该怎么做
You know how to find me. You know what you have to do.
很清晰吧
Sharp? No?
你没事吧 Cobb先生
Are you all right,Mr. Cobb?
放心 我没事
Yeah,yeah. I'm just fine.
Robert Fischer
Robert Fischer,
Fischer明日能源集团的继承人
heir to the Fischer-Morrow Energy Conglomerate.
你和这位小Fischer先生有什么过节
What's your problem with this Mr. Fischer?
这不用你管
That's not your concern.
斋藤先生 这...
Mr. Saito,this...
这可不是一般意义上的商业间谍活动
this isn't your typical corporate espionage.
你让我植入一个想法 我希望你能理解...
You asked me for inception,I do hope you understand that...
这其中的严重性
the gravity of that request.
我们植入目标大脑的这个想法
The seed that we plant in this man's mind will grow into an idea.
会界定他会成为一个怎样的人
This idea would define him. It may come to change...
甚至可能会彻底改变他的人生
it may come to change everything about him.
要不是我们公司 他们早就垄断全球的能源市场了
We're the last company standing between them and total energy dominance.
但我们快撑不住了
We can no longer compete.
很快他们将控制半个世界的能源供给
Soon they'll control the energy supply of half the world.
然后他们将成为新兴的强权帝国
In effect,they become a new superpower.
但只要小Fischer改变想法
The world needs Robert Fischer
世界就能得救
to change his mind.
所以你找上我们了
That's where we come in.
这个小Fischer
How is Robert Fischer's
和他父亲的关系如何
relationship with his father?
有传言说他们之间的关系有些纠结
Rumor is their relationship is quite complicated.
要完成任务 光靠传言可不够
But we can't work based solely on rumor,can we?
能帮我接近这个人吗
Can you get me access to this man here,
Browning
Browning?
老Fischer的左膀右臂
Fischer senior's right-hand man,
小Fischer的教父
Fischer junior's godfather.
应该不难 只要你有适当的引荐信
It should be possible,if you can get the right references.
不成问题 我的专长就是 各种伪造
References are something of a speciality for me,Mr. Saito.
看来这案子和解不了
I'm not smelling settlement here.
-把他们告倒  -Browning先生
- Take them down. - Mr. Browning,
老Fischer先生的原则之一
Maurice Fischer's policy is always one of
就是避免一切诉讼
avoiding litigation.
那我们要不要进去和老Fischer先生
Well,shall we voice your concerns
来个面对面交谈
with Maurice directly?
那也不用
Not sure if that's necessary.
不不 我可以去问问他
No,no,no. I think we should.
他怎么样了
How is he?
我也不想打扰他 但...
I don't wanna bother him unnecessarily,but...
小Fischer 我不是跟你说过
Robert,I've told you to
别让他们进来
keep out the damn...
照做有那么难吗
so do it!
老Fischer先生 你现在不适合讲话
No,don't speak,Mr. Fischer.
你啊 从来都没听过话
Never... never do as same as I asked.
别管那个了
Leave that.Here.
这肯定是他很珍贵的回忆
Must be a cherished memory of his.
我把相框放在他床边  他连看都没看一眼
I put it beside his bed. He hasn't even noticed it.
小Fischer 我们恐怕得谈谈你的继承权了
Robert,we need to talk about the power of attorney.
-我知道你很难过...  -现在不行 Peter叔叔
- I know this is hard for you...  - Not now,uncle Peter.
但刻不容缓 我们必须得开始准备了...
But it's imperative that we start to...
秃鹰已经在盘旋了
The vultures are circling.
老Fischer病得越重
It is the sicker Maurice Fischer becomes,
Browning就变得越有权力
The more powerful Peter Browning becomes.
我花了不少时间 来观察了Browning
I've had ample opportunity to observe Browning,
熟悉他的外貌身形 研究他的言谈举止和习惯等等
adopt his physical presence,study his mannerisms,so on and so forth.
所以 在梦境的第一层
So now,in the first layer of the dream,
我可以扮成Browning
I can impersonate Browning,
把想法暗示到Fischer的潜意识中
and suggest the concept to Fischer's conscious mind.
当我们带他进入第二层
Then,when we take him a level deeper,
他潜意识中所投影出来的Browning
his own projection of Browning should...
就会把这些想法反馈给他自己
should feed that right back to him.
-于是他以为那是他自己的想法  -没错
- So he gives himself the idea? - Precisely.
想要植入生根 必须让想法看起来是自己产生的
That's the only way it will stick. It has to seem self-generated.
Eames 我很佩服
Eames,I am impressed.
能得到你的表扬
Your condescension,as always,
我真是三生有幸 谢谢Arthur
is much appreciated,Arthur. Thank you.
你刚刚是一个人进入梦境吗
Were you going under on your own?
没什么 我就是做些实验
No,no. I was just,uh...  just running some experiments.
没想到这里还有别人 所以...
I didn't realize anyone was here. So...
嗯  其实我是在准备我的图腾
Yeah,I was just... I was working on my totem,actually.
过来 给我看看
Here,let me take a look.
学得不错
So you're learning,huh?
这样鉴别现实和梦境 好优雅啊
An elegant solution for keeping track of reality.
-是你想出来的  -不是  其实…….
- Was it your idea? - No,it was,uh...
其实是Mal想到的 这个...
It was Mal's,actually. This is...
以前是她的图腾
This one was hers.
在梦中旋转这个陀螺 它永远不会倒
She'd spin it in a dream and it would never topple,
会这么一直转下去
just spin and spin.
Arthur跟我说她过世了
Arthur told me she passed away.
迷宫设计得怎么样了
How are the mazes coming along?
根据我们要进入的 潜意识的不同部分
Each level relates to the part of the subject's
我设计了不同层次与之对应的梦境
subconscious that we're trying to access,so...
所以在最后一层设计成了医院
Making the bottom level hospital,
这样费舍就能见到他父亲...
so Fischer will bring his father,um...
可关于整个结构 我有个疑问
You know,actually I have a question about this layout...
别别别 千万不要告诉我细节
No,no,no. Don't... don't show me the specifics.
细节应该只有筑梦师知道
Only the dreamer should know the layout.
为什么要这样
Why's that so important?
以防我们中有人把自己的防御者也带进去
In case one of us brings in our projections,
不能让他们知道迷宫的细节
we don't want them knowing the details of the maze.
你是说如果Mal进来了
You mean in case you bring Mal in?
你也拦不住她 对吧
You can't keep her out,can you?
-是 -你之所以不能筑梦
- Right. - You can't build them because...
是因为你知道迷宫布局了 她也就知道了
if you know the maze,then she knows it.
她就会破坏整个行动
She'd sabotage the whole operation.
Cobb 其他人知道吗
Cobb,did the others know?
不 不知道
No,they don't.
万一情况变糟了 你应该告诉大家
You gotta warn them if this is getting worse.
谁说情况会变糟的
No one said it's getting worse!
我只想要回家
I need to get home.
这是我现在唯一关心的事情
That's all I care about right now.
你为什么不回不了家
Why can't you go home?
警察认为是我杀了她
Because they think I killed her.
-谢谢  -谢什么
- Thank you. - For what?
没有问我 是不是真的杀了她
For not asking whether I did.
"我要瓦解我父亲的帝国"
"I will split up my father's empire."
显然这个想法
Now this is obviously
会被小Fischer自己立刻否定掉
an idea that Robert himself would choose to reject.
所以我们得把这个想法
Just why we need to plant it
植入他潜意识深处
deep in his subconscious.
潜意识是被情感驱动的 对吗  不是理性
Subconscious is motivated by emotion,right? Not reason.
所以必须把情感元素融入到这个想法里
We need to find a way to translate this into an emotional concept.
怎么把一个商业策略转变成情感元素
How do you translate a business strategy into an emotion?
这不等着我们想办法么
That's what we have to figure out,right?
现在小Fischer与他父亲的关系
Now,Robert's relationship with his father is stressed,
至少已经很紧张了
to say the least.
能利用这点吗
Can we run with that,
让他觉得瓦解自己父亲的公司
we could suggest to him breaking up his
就是对老头子的一次反抗
father's company as a "screw you" to the old man?
这不行
No,
因为积极情感会压制消极情感
'cause I think positive emotion trumps negative emotion every time.
我们每个人都渴望和谐、精神上的宣泄
We all yearn for reconciliation,a catharsis.
我们必须让小Fischer
We need Robert Fischer
从正面产生这个想法
to have a positive emotional reaction to all this.
好吧 那这个怎么样
Alright,well,try this,um...
"我父亲希望我靠自己闯出一片天"
"my father accepts that I want to create for myself,
"而不是活在他的温室里"
not follow in his footsteps."
-有点意思 还行  -还行
- That might work. - Might?
只是还行怎么能行
We need to do a little better than "might".
"谢谢你的贡献" Arthur （Eames一直觉得他木 意思是Arthur什么也没想到）
Oh,thank you for your contribution,Arthur.
我只是想要个明确的思路
Forgive me for wanting a little specificities. Specificity?
要植入想法 可不能指望明确 进入他的大脑以后
Inception is not about being specific. When we get inside his mind,
我们只能见机行事
we're gonna have to work with what we find.
在第一层梦境  我们从他和父亲的紧张关系入手
On the top level,we open up his relationship with his father,
让他知道 "我不想再活在父亲的温室里"
say,"I will not follow in my father's footsteps."
然后到了第二层 让他意识到
Then the next level down,we feed him,
"我要靠自己闯出一片天"
"I will create something for myself."
最后在第三层 我们就亮出王牌
Then,by the time we hit the bottom level,we bring out the big guns...
-"父亲不想让我变成他"  -没错
- "my father doesn't want me to be him. - Exactly.
三层梦境很不稳定 稍有干扰
With three layers down,the dreams are gonna collapse...
梦境就会崩溃
with the slightest disturbance.
镇静剂 为了让你们
Sedation,for a sleep...
稳定地进入第三层梦境
stable enough to create three layers of dreaming.
得在催眠剂配方里加入强力镇静剂
We have to combine with an extremely powerful sedative.
好好睡
Good night.
我们梦境分享时 使用的催眠剂
The compound we'll be using to share the dream
会让做梦者之间产生非常清晰的联系
creates very clear connection between dreamers,
同时也会加快大脑运转速度
whilst actually accelerating brain function.
换句话说 每层梦境的时间都会变长
In other words,it gives us more time on each level.
大脑的运转速度会整整提高二十倍
Brain function in the dream will be about twenty times normal.
进入梦中梦 效果会叠加
When you enter a dream within that dream,the effect is compounded.
三层梦境 也就是十小时乘以二十...
Three dreams,that's ten hour times twenty...
不好意思
I'm sorry,uh...
我数学一向不好
math's never my strong subject.
-究竟是多长时间  -第一层是一周
- How much time is that? - It's a week the first level down.
第二层是半年 而第三层则是...
Six months the second level down. And the third level...
十年
Ten years.
谁愿意困在梦里长达十年
Who would wanna be stuck in a dream for ten years?
看是什么梦咯
Depends on the dream.
那我们成功植入以后 我们要怎么出来
So once we've made the plant,how do we get out?
指望你这回能优雅些
I'm hoping you have something more
我可不想你再冲我脑门开一枪
elegant in mind than shooting me in the head?
-穿越  -什么是穿越
- A kick.- What's a kick?
Ariadne 这就叫穿越
This,Ariadne,would be a kick.
通过一种强烈的撞击或下坠感 将你惊醒
It's that feeling of falling,you get the jolts to wake.
这样就能脱离梦境
It snaps you out of the dream.
用那么多镇静剂 能穿越吗
Are we gonna feel a kick with this kind of sedation?
妙就妙在这儿
Oh,that's the clever part.
我的镇静剂
I customize the sedative
绝对不会影响内耳的平衡功能
to leave inner ear function unimpaired.
这样 无论你睡得有多沉 都能感到坠落
That way,however deep the sleep,the sleeper still feels falling,
或倾倒
or tipping.
但关键的是 要让穿越同时穿透三层梦境 同步发生
The trick is to synchronize a kick that can penetrate all three levels.
可以用音乐倒计时
We can use a musical countdown
来同步所有的穿越
to synchronize different kicks.
他没预约外科手术、牙医 什么都没有
He hasn't any surgery schedule,no dental,nothing.
他不是该动个膝盖手术吗
Wasn't he supposed to have a knee operation?
没有 没有任何被麻醉的可能
Nothing. Nothing they'd put him under for,anyway. We need...
我们至少需要十小时
We need at least a good ten hours.
悉尼到洛杉矶
Sydney to Los Angeles,
世界上最长的航线之一
One of the longest flights in the world.
他每两周飞一次
He makes it every two weeks.
他肯定有私人飞机
And he must be flying private.
要是私人飞机突然出故障了
Not if there were unexpected maintenance with his plane.
-最好是波音747  -为什么
- It'd have to be a 747.- Why is that?
747的驾驶舱在顶上
Cause on a 747,pilots are up top,
头等舱在机头上
And the first class cabin's in the nose,
所以不会有闲人打扰
So no one would walk through.
但你得包下头等舱
But you'd have to buyout the entire cabin,
买通所有空乘
And the first class flight attendant.
我把那家航空公司买下来了
I bought the airline.
这样比较省事
It seemed neater.
看来我们有十个小时了
It looks like we have our ten hours.
Ariadne 那个 干得漂亮
Ariadne? Terrific work,by the way.
你知道怎么找到我
You know how to find me.
你知道你该怎么做
You know what you have to do.
还记得你向我求婚时说的话吗
You remember when you asked me to marry you?
-当然记得  -你说你做了一个梦
- Of course I do.- You said you had a dream.
-梦到我们一起慢慢变老  -我们会的
- That we grow old together.- And we can.
你来这干嘛
You shouldn't be in here.
我只是想看看
I just want to see what kind of
你每晚都在独自做什么"实验"
"tests" you're doing on your own every night.
这和你一点关系都没有
Whatever it was,it has nothing to do with you.
怎么会没关系
It has everything to do with me.
-你让我和你分享梦境  -不是分享这个
- You've asked me to share dreams with you.- Not these.
这是我自己的梦
These are my dreams.
你为什么要这么做
Why do you do this to yourself?
只有这样我才能继续做梦
This is the only way I can still dream.
为什么一定得做梦
Why is it so important to dream?
梦里 我跟她在一起
In my dreams we're still together.
这不仅仅是梦 这是你的记忆
These aren't just dreams. These are memories.
-你说过不能用记忆造梦  -我确实说过
- And you said never to use memories.- I know I did.
你想尽办法让她活着 你放不下她
You're trying to keep her alive.you can't let her go.
你不懂
You don't understand.
这些都是让我追悔不已的瞬间
These are moments I regret,
是我想改变的记忆
the memories that I have to change.
那这下面 有什么让你后悔的事
Well,what's down there that you regret?
听好 你不需要了解我所有的想法
Listen,there's only one thing you need to understand about me.
-这是你家  -我和Mal的家
- This is your house? - Mine and Mal's,yes.
-她人呢  -她已经不在了
- Where is she?  - She's already gone.
那是我儿子James
It's my son,James.
他最爱挖土 好像在挖虫子
He's digging for something,maybe a worm.
那是Philippa
That's Philippa.
知道吗 如果当时我叫他们一声
You see,I thought about calling out to them,
他们就能转过头来对我着我笑...
so they'd turn and smile and I can see those...
我就能看见他俩可爱的小脸 但...太晚了
Those beautiful faces of theirs.but... It's all too late.
再不走就来不及了 Cobb
Right now,or never,Cobb.
我当时就不知所措了
Then I start to panic.
我知道我将来肯定会后悔
I realize I don't wanna regret this moment,that I..
如果我不最后再看他们一眼的话
I need to see their faces one last time.
James  Philippa  快过来
James! Philippa! Come on in!
但我错过了机会
But the moment's passed.
后来不管我做什么都无法改变那一刻
Whatever I do I can't change this moment.
就在我想喊他们时 他们跑开了
When I'm about to call out to them,they run away.
我要想再见到他们 就一定得回家
If I'm ever gonna see their faces again,I've gotta get back home,
现实中的家
In the real world.
-你来这干嘛  -我叫...
- What are you doing here?  - My name is...
我知道你是谁 我问你来这干嘛
I know who you are.  What are you doing here?
-我只是想试着了解  -你怎么可能了解
- I'm just trying to understand.- How could you understand?
你知道什么叫相爱吗
Do you know what it is to be a lover?
-成为彼此另一半的感觉  -不知道
- To be half of a whole?  - No.
来猜个谜语吧
I'll tell you a riddle.
你在等一趟火车 它会把你带去远方
You're waiting for a train,a train that will take you far away.
你了然心之所向
You know where you hope this train will take you,
却不知火车开向何方
But you don't know for sure.
但这并不重要
But it doesn't matter.
为什么火车开向哪里不重要呢
How can it not matter to you where that train will take you?
因为我们会在一起
Because you'll be together.
Dom 你怎么能把她带过来
How could you bring her here,Dom?
这是什么地方
What is this place?
这是我们庆祝结婚纪念日的套房
This is a hotel suite where we spent our anniversary.
这里发生过什么
What happened here?
你向我承诺过 我们会在一起
You promised! you promised we'd be together!
求你了 留在这 暂时先留在这
Please,I need you stay here,just for now.
你说过我们会在一起 我们会一起慢慢变老
You said we'd be together! you said we'd grow old together!
我会回来找你 我保证
I'll come back for you,I promise.
你觉得建一座记忆监狱 就能关住她
Do you think you can just build a prison of memories to lock her in?
你觉得那里能关得住她吗
Do you really think that's gonna contain her?
是时候了 老Fischer刚在悉尼去世
It's time.Maurice Fischer just died in Sydney.
-葬礼什么时候  -星期四 在洛杉矶
- When's the funeral? - Thursday,in Los Angeles.
小Fischer必须在周二前去护送遗体
Robert should accompany the body no later than Tuesday.
出发吧
We should move.
-好  - Cobb 我跟你一起去
- Right. - Cobb,I'm coming with you.
我答应过我父亲不能让你去冒险 （筑梦师不必亲自进入梦境）
I promised Miles. No.
得有人了解你潜意识里的挣扎
The team needs someone who understands what you're struggling with.
不带上我也可以
And it doesn't have to be me,
但你得把我刚才看见的都告诉亚瑟
but then you have to show Arthur what I just saw.
在飞机上加个位子
Get us another seat on the plane.
如果我上了这飞机 你却不履行我们的协议
If I get on this plane,and you don't honor our agreement,
那着陆后 我就会在监狱里度过余生
When we land,I go to jail for the rest of my life.
在飞机上把活干完 到时我只要在飞机上打个电话
Complete the job en route,I make one phone call from the plane,
你就能顺利入境
You'll have no trouble getting through immigration.
-抱歉 借过  -啊 不好意思 挡住你了
- I'm sorry. - Oh,yeah. I'm sorry.
谢谢
Thank you.
打扰一下 这是你的吗 不小心掉了
Excuse me,I think this is yours?  You must've dropped it.
-两位想要喝点什么吗  -来杯水 谢谢
- Would you gentlemen care for a drink?  - Oh,water,please.
一样 谢谢
Same,please.
那个...谢谢
Umm... thank you.
那个 刚刚不小心看到的
You know,I couldn't help but notice,but...
你不会是那个著名的Maurice Fischer的亲戚吧
You wouldn't happen to be related to "the Maurice Fischer",will you?
对 没错 他...是我父亲
Yes,he,um... he was my father.
他是个很了不起的人 节哀顺变
He was a very inspiring figure. I'm sorry for your loss.
-给  -谢谢
- Here you go. - Thank you.
来 敬你父亲 愿他安息
Hey,to your father. May he rest in peace.
（Yusuf在喝香槟）
（下雨是Yusuf想上厕所的潜意识反应 第一层做梦者是Yusuf）
（分享梦境时 每个人的潜意识都会影响梦境 包括后来的火车）
-你睡前就不能去解个手么  -抱歉
- Couldn't you have peed before you went under. - Sorry.
一看到免费香槟 他就拼命喝
Bit too much free champagne before takeoff,Yusuf?
你就可劲儿笑吧
Aha,bloody ha.
雨这么大 他肯定在找出租车
Well now,he's gonna be looking for a taxi in this weather.
-你二啊 你丫怎么不...闪开
- Asshole! Hey man,why don't you try... - Walk away.
我得挂了 出租车 谢谢
I gotta go. Taxi! Thank you.
-那个 第三街区  -太给力了
Alright Third and Market  - Snappy!
-你干嘛  -哎呀 我以为空车
- What're you doing?  - I'm sorry. I thought it was free.
-当然不是  -那咱拼个车吧
- No,it's not. - Maybe we could share.
不行 靠边停让他...
Maybe not. Can you pull over to get this...
"太好了"
Great.
上来
Come on.
这里有五百美元
There's five hundred dollars in there,
而这钱包 还不止这个价
And the wallet's worth more than that.
-好歹送我到目的地吧  -这恐怕...
- So you might at least drop me at my stop.  - I'm afraid...
-保护他  -趴下 趴下
- Covering him!  - No! no! no!
这他妈搞什么呢
What was going on?
我可没设计这个
This wasn't in the design.
Cobb
Cobb. Cobb?
干掉他
Get him!
-你没事吧  -我没事 我很好 我很好
- Are you alright? - Yeah,I'm alright,I'm okey. I'm okey.
-小Fischer也没事 没准有点晕车  -斋藤
- Fischer's okey. Unless he gets carsick. - Saito?
把小Fischer关到里面去 快
Get Fischer in the back room,now.
-带进去 快  -天 这是怎么了...
- Get him in the back room. Move! - What the hell?
-他中枪了 会死吗  -我不知道
- Has he been shot? Is he dying? - I don't know.
我的祖宗啊
Jesus Christ!
你们去哪儿了 出什么事了
Where were you? what happened to you?
我们被一列火车截住了
We were blocked by a freight train.
你怎么能在市中心的路口
Why would you put a train crossing in
放一列火车
The middle of a downtown intersection?
-我没有  -那火车哪儿来的
- I didn't.- Where did it come from?
我才要问你呢 我们怎么会被人攻击的
Lemme ask you a question! Why the hell we were ambushed,huh?
那些人都不是普通的防御者
Those were not normal projections.
他妈的他们都是受过训练的好不好
He'd been trained,for god's sakes!
-没错  -谁会训练他们
- You're right.- How could he be trained?
小Fischer肯定请盗梦者教过他
Fischer's had an extractor teach his subconscious
潜意识防卫 所以...
to defend itself. so...
他的防御者都是武装过的 早期我应该做好调查的
His subconscious is militarized. This should have shown in the research.
-对不起  -那你他妈早期都调查什么了
- I'm sorry.- Why the hell you didn't?
-冷静点  -冷静你个头啊
- Calm down. - Don't tell me to calm down!
这是你分内的事 你他妈要负全责
This was your job,goddamnit! This was your responsibility!
你应该把他的底细调查清楚
You were meant to check Fischer's background thoroughly!
对这种袭击 我们完全没有防备
We are not prepared for this type of fire!
我们之前不也碰过潜意识防卫情况吗
We have dealt with the subsecurity before.
只要小心一点不就行了
We'll be a little more careful.we're gonna be fine.
之前可没有这种状况 他快死了 我的祖宗啊
"Before" is not a part of the plan! He's dying,for god's sake!
-把他叫醒  -别 千万别
- Let's put him out of his misery. - Don't do that! Don't do that!
他太痛苦了 我要把他叫醒
He's in agony. I'm waking him up.
不行 你唤不醒他的
No,it won't wake him up.
-说什么呢 什么叫醒不来 -就是他醒不了
- What do you mean,it won't wake him up? - It won't wake him up.
在梦里死去 不就能醒过来嘛
When we die in a dream,we wake up.
这次不行了
Not from this.
我们用的镇静剂太强了
We're too heavily sedated to wake up that way.
妈呀 那死了会怎样
Right. so what happens when we die?
-坠入迷失域（潜意识边缘）  -开什么国际玩笑
- Drop into limbo. - Are you serious?
-什么迷失域  -最荒芜的梦境
- Limbo?  - Unconstructed dream space.
那里有什么
What the hell is down there?
除了原始和无穷的潜意识
Just raw infinite subconscious.
本应什么都没有
Nothing is down there,
除非有人之前困在那里
except for whatever might have been left behind
自行建造 留下了一些场景碎片
by anyone sharing the dream who's been trapped there before,
在我们中间就只有你去过
Which in our case is just you.
我们在那里会困多久
But how long could we be stuck there?
在镇静剂消退前 是不可能逃出来的
Not even think about trying to escape until the sedation eases...
问你多久
How long?
几十年 也许是永远 我怎么知道
Decades,it could be infinite,I don't know.
问他吧 只有他去过
Ask him. he's the one who's been there.
先把他抬楼上去再说
Let's just get him upstairs.
"太给力了"  "谢谢啊"
Great. Thank you.
我们现在 困在小Fischer的潜意识里
So,now we are trapped in Fischer's mind
跟他的武装防御军队拼老命
battling his own private army.
要是一不小心挂了
And if we get killed,
就会跌进迷失域
we'll be lost in limbo
直到脑子烧坏 是吧
till our brains turn to scrambled egg. hmm?
有急救箱吗
You got first aid?
你明知道有危险 却没有告诉我们
So you knew about these risks. You didn't tell us?
不应该有危险的
There wasn't meant to be any risk.
我怎么知道我们会被袭击
I didn't know we'd be dealing with a load of gunfire.
你不该瞒着我们的
You had no right.
这是深入三层梦境的唯一方式
This is the only way to go three layers deep.
还有你啊 明知其中风险 也不吱个声
And you,you knew about this and went along with it?
我相信他啊
I trusted him.
信你个头 你相信钱吧 他把他那份钱分你一半
You trusted him? When? When he promised you half his share?
没有 他说全给我
No,his whole share.
而且他说他以前干过
Besides,he said he had done it before.
干过 和Mal那次吗
You had done it before? What? With Mal?
-那次什么下场  -那次和现在没关系
- Cause that works so good? - That has nothing to do with it.
我只是竭尽所能回到我的孩子身边
I did what I had to do to get back to my children.
所以你就把我们领向一条不归路
So you led us into a war zone with no way out?
不是绝路 好吗
There's a way out,alright?
大家继续按计划行事 速战速决
We continue on with the job,and we do this as fast as possible,
然后和以前一样 用穿越离开梦境
And we get out using the kick,just like before.
拉倒吧 走得越深我们就越危险
Forget it. If we go any deeper,we just raise the stakes.
老子不走了 俺就留在这一层 坐着等醒
I am sitting this one hour on this level,worse?
我们吵架这会功夫
Fischer's security is surrounding this place
小Fischer的防御军队正在包围这里
Fischer's security is surrounding this place as we speak.
十小时的航线 在这一层就是一个礼拜
The ten hours of flight time is a week at this level.
也就是说 不尽快完成任务 而继续留在这
That means each and every one of us will be killed,that I can guarantee.
一个礼拜后 我们早就全部死光光了
We have no other choice but to continue on and do it as fast as possible.
要想逃出去 只能继续往下走
Downwards,is the only way forwards.
准备开工 你跟我来
Get ready. You,come on.
我们去"照顾照顾"他
Let's go shake him up.
（如此淡定...）
赎金在一千万之内 我可以马上支付
I'm insured against kidnaping for up to ten million.
要钱很简单
This should be very simple.
闭嘴 没那么简单
Shut up! It won't be.
你老爸办公室的书橱下 有个保险箱
In your father's office,below the bookshelves,is his personal safe.
-密码是什么  -我不知道有什么保险箱
- We need the combination. - I don't know any safe.
那不代表你不知道密码 快告诉我们
It doesn't mean you don't know the combination. Tell us what it is.
我真不知道
I don't know.
我们情报是不会出错的
We have it on good authority you do know.
是吗 那谁说的
Yeah? Who's this authority?
-这玩意居然值五百美元  -打开看看
- Five hundred dollars this cost. - Open inside.
现金 各种卡 身份证 还有这个
Cash,cards,ID,and this.
（被用在第三层梦里）
-用得上吗  -也许吧
- Useful? - Maybe.
-轮你上场了 一个小时  -就一小时啊
- You're on. you've got an hour. - An hour?
不是说好给我一晚上时间吗
I was supposed to have all night to crack this.
那斋藤胸口说好中枪了吗
Saito wasn't supposed to be shot in the chest.
一小时 挖出点有用的 拜托
Got one hour to get something useful,please.
什么声音
What's that?
听不出来吗
Good authority.
Peter叔叔
Uncle Peter.
-先让他们住手  -密码是多少
- Just... just make them stop. - The combination?
-我真不知道  -那为什么Browning说你知道
- I don't know it.- What does Browning say you do.
他说的 那个...让我先跟他谈谈
I don't know. Just lemme... lemme talk to him,
再说吧
and I'll find out.
给你一小时 谈吧
You have one hour. Start talking.
你还好吧
Are you okey?
这帮混蛋关了我整整两天
Those bastards've had me for two days.
他们派人潜入了你父亲的办公室
They have someone with access to your father's office.
-试图打开他的保险箱  -我知道
- And they're trying to open his safe.- Yeah.
他们以为我知道密码 可我不知道
They thought I'd know the combination,but I don't know it.
-其实 我也不知道 所以...  -什么
- Yeah,well,neither do I. so... - What?
你父亲跟我说我 在他走后
Maurice told me that when he passed,
你是唯一知道密码的人
you are the only one to be able to open it.
没有...他从没告诉过我什么密码
No,he never... he never gave me any combination.
说不定他说过了呢
Maybe he did,I mean,
只是你不知道那就是密码
maybe you just didn't know it was a combination.
-那 像是什么  -不清楚
- Well,what then? - I don't know.
不过肯定是一些 意义重大的数字
Some meaningful combination of numbers based on your...
你和你父亲的一些共同经历有关的
your experiences with Maurice.
我们没什么...有意义的共同经历
We didn't have very many,um... meaningful experiences together.
或许 在你妈妈去世后
Perhaps,after your mother died.
我妈去世后 你知道他跟我说什么吗
After my mother died,you know what he told me?
"小Fischer 其实没什么好说的"
"Robert,there's really nothing to be said."
别较真 他不善表达情感
Oh,he was bad with emotions.
我当时才十一岁啊 Peter叔叔
I was eleven,uncle Peter.
-他怎么样  -很痛苦
- How's he doing? - He's in a lot of pain.
等我们到下面几层 疼痛感就会减弱
When we get down to the lower levels,the pain will be less intense.
-他要是死了呢  -你说最坏情况
- And if he dies? - The worst case scenario?
醒来后 会完全丧失意识
When he wakes up,his mind is completely gone.
Cobb 我仍会履行我们的协议
Cobb,I'll still honor the arrangement.
我很感激 但是斋藤...
I appreciate that,Saito. But..
你醒来后 根本不会记得我们曾有过协议
When you wake up,you won't even remember that we had an arrangement.
你会留在迷失域（潜意识边缘）
Limbo's gonna become your reality.
你会困在那里
You're gonna be lost down there so
等到年华逝去
long that you're gonna become an old man.
-在悔恨中度过余生  -孤零零地等死
- Filled with regret. - Waiting to die alone?
不 我会回来 和你们一起重回年轻
No,I'll come back. and we'll be young men,together again.
深呼吸
Breathe.
如果我们不说出密码
These people are gonna kill us here,
这伙人会马上杀了我们
if we don't give them the combination.
-他们不过是想要钱  -我听到他们说了
- They just want a ransom. - I heard them.
他们会把我们塞进货车 把车丢进河里喂鱼
They're gonna whack us in that van and then drive it into the river.
好吧 那保险箱里到底有什么
Alright,what is it in the safe?
是留给你的东西
Something for you.
你父亲总说 那是他留给你最珍贵的礼物
Maurice always said it was his most precious gift to you.
-一份遗嘱  -遗嘱不是给律师了吗
- A will.  - Maurice's will is with Port and Dunn.
这份是候补遗嘱
That's an alternate.
如果你愿意 完全可以推翻前一份
This would supersede the other,if you want it to.
这份遗嘱是讲 要你解散费舍明日能源集团
It splits up the component businesses of Fischer-Morrow,
你父亲的能源帝国会从此消失
and it'd be the end of the entire empire as we know it.
不留给我一丝一毫吗
Destroy my whole inheritance?
-他为什么要我这么做  -我也不知道
- Why would he suggest such a thing? - I just don't know.
他很爱你 小Fischer 以他独特的方式
He loved you,Robert,in his own way.
以他独特的方式
In his own way?
他临终前 把我叫到他床边
At the end,he called me to his deathbed.
虽然几乎说不了话了
He could barely speak.
但仍耗尽最后一口气 说了最后一句话
But he took the trouble to tell me one last thing.
他让我凑上去
He pulled me close.
我只勉强听清了两个字
And I could only make out one word --
"失望"
"disappointed."
你什么时候进入过迷失域
When were you in limbo?
虽然你成功说服了大家继续执行任务
You might have the rest of the team convinced to carry on with this job,
-但他们并不知道真相  -什么真相
- But they don't know the truth? - Truth? What truth?
真相就是 任何时候你都有可能
The truth that at any minute,
让一列火车撞进来
you might bring a freight train through the wall.
真相就是 你无法控制你潜意识里的Mal
The truth that Mal is bursting through your subconscious.
真相就是 我们不断深入小Fischer意识的同时
And the truth that as we go deeper into Fischer,
也会不断受到你潜意识的干扰
We're also going deeper into you.
我不知道接下来还会发生什么
And I'm not sure we're gonna like what we find.
我当时在和她一起工作
We were working together.
我们在研究在梦里做梦的可能性
We were exploring the concept of a dream within a dream.
我不断给自己压力 想要研究的更深
I kept pushing things. I wanted to go deeper and deeper.
研究的更透彻
I wanted to go further.
我当时还没意识到
I just didn't understand the concept
现实的几小时会变成梦中的几年
that hours could turn into years down there,
我们陷得太深了
And we could get trapped so deep that only
最终到达潜意识边缘的时候
wound up on the shore of our own subconscious.
已经无法分辨梦境和现实
We lost sight of what was real.
我们为自己创造了一个世界
We created and built a world for ourselves.
我们建了很多年
We did that for years.
建起了只属于我们自己的世界
We built our own world.
-你们被困了多久  -大概有五十年吧
- How long were you stuck there? - Something like fifty years.
天呐 你们怎么能受得了
Jeez. How could you stand it?
一开始还不错 感觉自己像上帝一样
It wasn't so bad at first,feeling like gods.
但问题是这些都不是真的
The problem was none of them was real.
最后 我终于无法忍受了
Eventually,it just became impossible for me to live like that.
那她怎么想
And what about for her?
她把自己内心深处的秘密锁起来了
She had locked something away,something deep inside her.
对于她曾经了解的现实
The truth that she had once known,
她选择将其遗忘
but she chose to forget.
她把迷失域当成了现实世界
Limbo became her reality.
你们醒来后发生了什么
What happened when you woke up?
在梦里呆了那么久 等到几十年后醒来
Well,to wake up from that after... after years,after decades,
苍老的灵魂重新回到年轻的躯体
We come old souls thrown back into youth like that.
我知道她有点不对劲
I knew something was wrong with her.
只是她自己不愿承认
she just wouldn't admit it.
她最终告诉了我真相
Eventually,she told me the truth.
长期以来 一个一直挥之不去的想法
She was possessed by an idea.
这个非常简单却能颠覆一切的想法
This one very simple idea that changed everything,
她觉得我们还在做梦
That our world wasn't real,
她必须醒过来回到现实世界
That she needed to wake up to come back to reality,that...
想要回去 我们俩都必须自杀
In order to get back home,we had to kill ourselves.
那你们的孩子呢
What about your children?
她说他们也不是真的
she thought they were projections,
我们真正的孩子正在现实中等着我们
That our real children were waiting for us up there somewhere.
-我是孩子的妈妈  -冷静点
- I am their mother. - Calm down.
你以为我看不出区别吗
Don't you think I can't tell the difference?
如果我在做梦 为什么我会控制不了它
If this is my dream,why can't I control this?
因为你不知道自己在做梦
Because you don't know you're dreaming!
她是如此坚决 不管我怎么解释
She was certain there was nothing I can do,
也不管我怎么求她 都无济于事
No matter how much I begged,no matter how much I pleaded.
她想回去 但她又不想一个人走
She wanted to do it,but she could not do it alone.
她太爱我了 所以...
She loved me too much,so...
在我们结婚纪念日那天 她想了一个办法
She came up with the plan on our anniversary.
-亲爱的 你在干什么  -一起来吧
- Sweetheart,what are you doing? - Join me.
你先退回屋里 好吗
Just... just step back inside. Alright?
退回屋里 求你了
Just step back inside. now,come on.
不
No.
我要跳下去 我们一起跳下去
I'm going to jump. And you are coming with me.
不 我不能跳
No,I'm not.
你听我说
Now... now you listen to me.
如果你跳下去 是不会醒的 明白吗
If you jump,you're not gonna wake up. Remember?
会死不会醒 所以先退回屋里去 好吗
You're gonna die. now just... just step back inside.
求你了
Come on!
回到屋里 我们好好谈谈
Step back inside so we can talk about this.
我们谈得够多了
we've talked enough.
Mal
Mal.
你快跨出来 不然我现在就跳下去
Come out onto the ledge,or I'll jump right now.
好
Okey.
我们先谈谈 好吗
Let's talk about this. Alright?
-这一次你要完全相信我  -不 亲爱的
- I'm asking you to take a leap of faith. - No,honey,
我不能跳 你知道我不会跳的
I can't. you know I can't do that.
为孩子们想想
Take a second to think about our children.
想想James 想想Phillipa
Think about James,think about Phillipa,now.
但你不和我跳 孩子们还是会被带走的
If I go without you,they'll take them away,anyway.
-什么意思  -我找律师留下了一封信
- What does that mean? - I filed a letter with our attorney,
信中说我一直为自己的安全担心
explaining how I'm fearful for my safety,
因为你威胁要杀了我
How you threatened to kill me.
-你为什么这么做  -我爱你 Dom
- why did you do this? - I love you,Dom.
你为什么这么对我 为什么 为什么
Why did you... why... why would you do this to me?
这样你就不会因离开孩子而内疚
Freed you from the guilt of choosing to leave them.
我们要回真正的家和孩子团聚了
We are going home,to our real children.
不不不 Mal 听我说 好吗
No,no... no. Mal,you listen to me,alright?
Mal 看着我 求你了
Mal,look at me,please!
你在等一趟火车
you're waiting for a train,
Mal 上帝啊 不要这样
Mal,goddamnit! Don't do this!
它会把你带去远方
a train that will take you far away.
James和Phillipa在等你回去
James and Phillipa are waiting for you!
你了然心之所向
You know where you hope this train will take you,
-他们在等我们  -却不知火车开向何方
- They're waiting for us! - But you don't know for sure.
-Mal 看着我  -但这并不重要
- Mal,look at me! - But it doesn't matter,
-Mal 上帝啊  -因为我们会在一起
- Mal,goddamnit! - Because we'll be together.
亲爱的 看着我
Sweetheart,look at me.
Mal 不要 老天爷啊
Mal! No! Jesus Christ!
她找了三个心理医生 证明她心智正常
She had herself declared sane by three different psychiatrists,
她让我没有任何办法去解释
That made it impossible for me to
她的内心有多么疯狂
Try to explain the nature of her madness.
所以我只能逃亡
So I ran.
再不走就来不及了 Cobb
Right now,or never,Cobb.
好吧 我们走
Alright,let's go.
我丢下了我的孩子
I left my children behind,
自那以后我就一直想办法回去
And I've been trying to buy my way back ever since.
你的罪恶感塑造了她 她才如此强大
Your guilt defines her,it's what powers her.
她的意念毁了自己 你不需要为她的死负责
But you are not responsible for the idea that destroyed her.
如果我们想要完成任务的话
And if we're gonna succeed in this,
你必须原谅自己
you have to forgive yourself,
坦然面对心中的她
And you're gonna have to confront her.
但你不必孤身奋战
But you don't have to do that alone.
不不 你不能...
No,you don't...
我这是为了大家
I'm doing it for the others.
因为他们完全不知道
Because they have no idea of the risk
和你一起深入梦境有多危险
they've taken coming down here with you.
我们得走了
We have to move.
-时间到了  -听着
- Time's up. - All right.
我不知道什么密码 至少在清醒时是不知道的
I don't know any combination,not consciously anyway.
那问问你的第六感
How about instinctively,huh?
现在 我们有人你父亲的保险箱前
I've got somebody standing in your father's office.
就等着输入密码了
Right now,we need to tap in the combination.
凭第一反应 说出六位数字 快
We need the first six numbers that come to your head right now.
-我想不出  -快说
- I have no idea. - Right now!
马上给我说出来
I said right now! Right now!
528  491
5...2...8...491.
"里叔'很生气 后果很严重
You'd have to do better than that.
好了 把他们蒙起来
Alright,bag them.
我们开车出去兜一圈
We're going for a ride.
我们死了 你们就什么也得不到了
We're worth much more to you alive...
你听到了吗
You hear me?
有什么收获
What did you get?
他们父子间的关系比我们想象的还糟
That boy's relationship with his father is even worse than we imagined.
这有什么用
This helps us how?
问题越严重 就越需要精神宣泄
The stronger the issues,the more powerfully cathartic.
你要怎么帮他们制造大和解
How are you gonna reconcile them of so estranged?
-我不正在想嘛  -给我快点
- Well,I'm working on that,an't I? - Move fast.
警卫队快包围这里了
The projections are closing in quick.
我们得赶快突围
we gotta break out of here,
不然就真挂在这了
Before we're totally boxed in.
该死
Damn it!
亲爱的 怕什么 做梦就得做大点
You mustn't be afraid to dream a little bigger,darling.
现在我们得把他对父亲的怨恨
Now,we need to shift his animosity
转移到他的教父身上
from his father to his godfather.
能做到吗 有那么容易吗
Would this destroy his one positive relationship?
这样
No,
我们就能一边修复他们父子间的关系
We'll repair his relationship with his
一边揭露他邪恶教父的真面目
father by exposing his godfather's true nature.
真是的 小Fischer该付我们心理咨询费的
Hell,we should charge Fischer much more than Saito.
怎么对付他的武装防御军队
What about his security?
走得越深 越难对付
It's gonna get worse as we go deeper.
是不是可以找找"查尔斯先生"
Now,I think we run with Mr. Charles.
不要
No.
-"查尔斯先生"是谁  -我不喜欢"查尔斯先生"
- Who's Mr. Charles? - Bad idea.
在第二层 只要我们走进酒店 一接近小Fischer
The second we get into that hotel and approach Fischer,
他的警卫队就会蜂拥而至
His security's gonna be all over us.
我们可以找"查尔斯先生"帮帮忙
We run with Mr. Charles
就跟以前一样
like we did on the Stein Job.
-这么说你们做过  -试过 但失败了
- So you've done it before? - Yeah,it didn't work.
目标意识到了自己在做梦
The subject realized that he was dreaming,
他的防御者将我们撕成了碎片
And his subconscious tore us to pieces.
这经历有意思 但吸取教训了 对吧
Excellent. but you've learnt a lot,right?
-得有人分散目标注意力才行  -没问题
- I need some kind of distraction. - No problem.
还记得上次那个美女吗
How about a lovely lady I've used before.
-听着 你小心开车  -好
- Listen to me. you drive carefully,alright? - Yeah.
接下来的一层会非常不稳定
The thing down there's gonna be unstable as hell.
（做梦者不能深入下一层 必须在本层继续做梦 最后负责同步穿越 ）
（所以Yusuf一直在第一层开车 ）
别跳得太早
Don't jump too soon.
我们只有一次穿越的机会
We only have one shot at that kick you're gonna make.
到时候我会放音乐
I'll play the music,then you'll know it's coming.
剩下的就看你们的了
the rest is on you.
-准备好了  -好了
- Are you ready? - Ready!
好梦
Sweet dreams!
很无聊 是吗
Am I boring you?
都是我一直在讲 你是不是没兴趣了
I was telling you my story. I guess it wasn't your liking.
啊 没有 我心里很乱
Oh,um... I have a lot in my mind.
"查尔斯先生"出场了
There goes Mr. Charles.
小Fischer先生
Mr. Fischer? Right?
很高兴再见到您 我是营销部的 Rod Green
Pleasure to see you again. Rod Green from marketing.
-那么你是...  -我是 失陪了
- And you must be...? - Leaving.
如果你寂寞的话
In case you get bored...
你们没戏的
Must have blown you off.
除非她的号码真只有六位数
That is unless her phone number,really is only six digits.
( 528 491)
-这么随便搭讪陌生人
Funny way down,make friends,
钱包很容易被偷啊
someone stealing their wallet like that.
该死 光那钱包就值...
Ha,goddamnit! Wallet alone is worth at least...
五百美元吗
About 500 dollars,right?
不用担心 我已经派我的人去找了
Listen,don't worry about it. My people are already on it as we speak.
谁是"查尔斯先生"
Who or what is Mr. Charles?
这招是用来诱使小Fischer对抗自己的潜意识
It's a gambit designed to turn Fischer against his own subconscious.
那你为什么不同意
Then why don't you approve?
因为必须告诉目标他在做梦
'cause it involves telling the mark that he's dreaming,
这样的话就会招来很多麻烦
Which involves attracting a lot of attention on us.
Cobb不是说不能这么做吗
Didn't Cobb say never to do that?
发现了啊 Cobb口中的禁忌
So now you've noticed how much time
他自己总是一犯再犯
Cobb spends doing things he says never to do.
斋藤先生 有空吗
Mr. Saito,can I have a moment?
啊 不好意思
Oh,I... I'm sorry.
等等
Wait!
-你气色好多了  -兴致真好 Eames先生
- You look a bit perkier. - Very amusing,Mr. Eames.
飞机遇到气流了
Turbulence on the plane?
不 第一层 是Yusuf在开车
No,it's much closer. It's Yusuf's driving.
-不好意思  你刚说你是谁来着  -营销部的Rod Green
- I'm sorry,who did you say you were? - Rod Green from marketing.
其实这不是真的 对吧
That's not true at all,is it?
我的名字是"查尔斯先生" 我们见过
My name is Mr. Charles. You remember me,don't you?
我是你在这的安全主管
I'm the head of your security down here.
到其他楼层下电梯 一直走别停下
Get out on a different floor and keep moving.
-扔了钱包 警卫会来找的  -好
- Dump the wallet. The security will look for that. - Okey.
我们得为Coob多争取点时间
We need to buy Cobb a little more time.
安全主管
Security,huh?
-你是这间酒店里的  -不 不
- You work for the hotel? - No,no.
我专门负责安全类别 非常非常特殊
I specialize in a very specific type of security,
潜意识安全
subconscious security.
你是说梦境吗
Are you talking about dreams?
或者说盗梦
Are you talking about,um... extraction?
我是来这保护你的
I'm here to protect you.
小Fischer先生 我之所以过来保护你
Mr.Fischer,I'm here to protect you
是因为有人利用梦境来进入你的大脑
In the event that someone tries access to your mind through your dreams.
这里不安全 他们已经冲着你来了
You are not safe here. They are coming for you.
天气很诡异吧
Strange weather,isn't it?
感觉到了吗
You feel that?
出什么事了
What's happening?
Cobb正设法让小Fischer意识到自己在做梦
Cobb's drawing Fischer's attention to the strangeness of the dream,
他的潜意识已经开始寻找做梦者了
which is making his subconscious look for the dreamer,
也就是我 快 亲下
For me. Quick,give me a kiss.
（第二层做梦者是Arthur）
-他们还在看啊  -呀 没骗过 不过值了
- They're still looking at us. - Yeah,it's worth a shot.
我们还是走吧
We should probably get out of here.
感觉到了吗
Do you feel that?
小Fischer先生 你应该受过专门的训练
You've actually been trained for this,Mr. Fischer.
注意天气的反常和重力的变向
Pay attention to the strangeness of the weather,the shift of the gravity.
这一切都不是真的 你在做梦
None of this is real. You're in a dream.
有个最简单的证明方法 回想一下
Now,the easiest way for you to test yourself is to try to remember,
你是怎么来到这家酒店的吗
How you arrived at this hotel. Can you do that?
记得  但我...
Yeah,I don't,I...
放松 深呼吸 想想你受过的训练
Now,breathe,breathe. Remember your training,
你必须意识到你是在梦里 我是来保护你的
Accept the fact that you're in the dream,and I'm here to protect you.
继续想想
Go on.
-你不是真人  -对 我不是
- You're not real? - No,no.
我是你潜意识里的防御者
I'm a projection of your subconscious.
我的任务就是保护你
I was sent here to protect you in the event
阻止任何盗梦者偷走你的信息
that the extractors try to pull you into a dream.
小Fischer先生 他们现在肯定在行动
And I believe that's what's going on right now,Mr. Fischer.
好吧
Yeah,okey.
我知道了
Okey.
-能救我出去吗 -当然 跟我来
- Can you get me out of here? - Right away. Follow me.
天啊 你这是干什么
This is what? What're you doing?
他们是被派来绑架你的  知道吗
These men were sent here  to abduct you,alright?
想要我救你 你得保持冷静
If you want my help,you have to remain calm.
小Fischer先生 你得和我合作才行
I need you to work with me,Mr. Fischer.
如果这是梦 只要自杀就能醒 对吗
If this is a dream,I should just kill myself to wake up. Right?
小Fischer先生 换做我就不会这么做
I wouldn't do that if I were you,mr. fischer.
他们肯定对你用了镇静剂
I believe that they have you sedated.
如果你扣动扳机 就醒不过来了
If... if you pull that trigger,you may not wake up.
很可能坠入更深层的梦里
You may go into a further dream state now.
明白我的意思吗
You know what I'm talking about.
回想下受过的训练和我说的话
You remember the training. Remember what I said to you.
把枪给我
Give me the gun.
房间：491 528（第一层的数字）
-这房间在528房间正下方吧 -没错
- This room should be directly below 528? - Yeah.
(在491炸毁528 使他们坠落)
回忆一下 小Fischer先生
Think,Mr. Fischer,think.
记不记得在这个梦境之前你在做什么
What do you remember from before this dream?
好像发生了很激烈的枪战...
Oh... there was,um... there was a lot of gunfires.
还下着大雨...
There was... rain.
Peter叔叔
Uncle Peter.
-天呐 我们被绑架了  -你们被关在哪里
- Oh my god,we've been kidnaped. - Where were they holding you?
-关在一辆面包车后面  -原来你们在行驶的面包车里
- They had us in the back of a van. - That explains the gravity shifts.
难怪重力会变向 继续
You're in the back of a van right now. Ke...keep going!
好像...和一个保险箱有关
It had something to do with,um... something to do with a... a safe.
天呐 好难啊 想不起来
God,why is it so hard to remember?
这就像你醒来回想自己的梦一样难
It's like trying to remember a dream after you've woken up.
大部分的人是做不到的
Listen to this,it takes years of practice.
你和Browning被拖进了这个梦境
You and Browning have been pulled into this dream,
说明有人想从你的大脑里偷走某样东西
Because they're trying to steal something from your mind.
集中精神 再好好想想那是什么
I need you to focus and try to remember what that is.
他们想要什么 再想想 小Fischer先生
What is it,Mr. Fischer? Think!
是一组密码
Uh... a combination.
他们要我凭第一感觉 说出几个数字
They demanded the first numbers that popped into my head.
他们想从你的潜意识里偷取一串数字
They were trying to extract the number from your subconscious.
这可能代表任何东西 我们现在酒店里
It can represent anything. We are in a hotel right now.
也许是房间号码 那组数字是什么 小Fischer先生
Should try hotel rooms. What was the number,Mr. Fischer?
快努力回想下 这很重要
Try and remember for me. This is very important.
5 5 2 这串数字很长
5...52... it was something long number...
能记起两个
That's good enough.
已经很好了
We could start there.
-是五楼  -收到
- Fifth floor. - Yep.
-要用定时炸弹吗  -不行 要自己判断引爆时间
- So do you use a timer? - No,I have to judge it for myself.
你们去528 继续做梦时
While you're all asleep in 528.
我来等Yusuf的穿越信号
I wait for Yusuf's kick.
-你怎么知道  -他会放音乐提醒我
- Well,how will you know? - His music warns me.
然后面包车会撞上桥边的护栏
And then when the van hits the barrier of the bridge,
准确无误 我们就能完美地同步穿越
That should be unmistakable. So we get a nice,synchronized kick.
如果太早引爆 你们来不及
If it's too soon,we won't get pulled out.
如果晚了 你们也无法坠落
And if it's too late,I won't be able to drop this.
-为什么  -面包车已经在自由落体
- Why not? - Because of the van that will be in free fall.
-没有重力就无法坠落  -有道理
- Can't drop you without gravity. - Right.
自己人
They're with me.
(房间：528)
-"查尔斯先生"  -小Fischer先生
- Mr. Charles. - Do you know
你知道这是什么吗
what that is,Mr. Fischer?
我想我知道
Yeah,I... I think so. yeah.
他们想把你拖入梦境里
They were trying to put you under.
-可我已经在了  -下一层梦境
- I'm already under. - Under again.
什么意思 你说在梦里还能做梦
What do you mean? A... Dream within a dream?
-呦呵 换了身行头  -什么
- Hey,I see you've changed. - I'm sorry?
抱歉 我把你当成我朋友了
Oh... I'm sorry. I've mistaken you for a friend.
那他一定很帅
Good looking fella,I'm sure.
那是小Fischer潜意识里的Browning
That's Fischer's projection of Browning.
跟着他 看看他会做什么
Let's follow him and see how he behaves.
-为什么  -从他身上就能看出来
- Why? - Because how he acts would tell us...
小Fischer要是对Browning产生了怀疑的话
If Fischer's starting to suspect his motives as the way we wanted to.
-Peter叔叔  -你们不是一起被绑架的吗
- Uncle Peter? - You said you were kidnaped together?
也不是 其实...
Well,um... well,not... not exactly.
他们先抓了他 还一直在拷打他
They... they already had him.they were torturing him.
你亲眼看到的
And you saw them torture him?
（"潜意识Browning"能找到528 是第一层的暗示 在第二层反馈给小Fischer自己 ）
（这里其实是小Fischer一个人的内心对话）
那些绑匪是你的人
AThe kidnapers are working for you?
小Fischer
Oh,Robert...
你要打开保险箱  拿走那份候补遗嘱
You're trying to get that safe open? So you get the alternate will?
我为公司投入了一生的心血
Fischer-Morrow has been my entire life.
我不能让你毁掉它
I can't let you destroy it.
我怎么可能会亲手毁掉自己的家业呢
I'm not gonna throw away my inheritance! Why would I?
我不忍让你看到你父亲对你最后的嘲弄
I couldn't let you rise to your father's last taunt.
什么嘲弄
What taunt?
就是那份遗嘱 小Fischer
The will,Robert.
是他对你莫大的羞辱
That will,that's his last insult,a challenge for you...
他觉得你只是个什么都靠他的富二代
you'd build something for yourself,
你不配继承他的巨额财富
by telling you you're not worthy of his accomplishments.
-是啊 他的确对我很失望  -对不起
- Well,that he was,um... disappointed. - Hmm,I'm sorry.
但是他错了
But... he's wrong.
因为你会超越他的成就 靠你自己
You can build a better company than he ever did.
-小Fischer先生 他在说谎  -你怎么知道
- Mr. Fischer,he's lying. - How do you know?
相信我 我就是干这行的
Trust me,it's what I do.
他有什么瞒着你
He's hiding something,
一定要搞清楚他到底想做什么
And we need to find out what that is.
我要你以其人之道还治其人之身
I need you to do the same thing to him that he was going to do to you.
我们要进入他的潜意识
We'll enter his subconscious and
把他的秘密全都挖出来
find out what he doesn't want you to know.
好吧
All right.
他睡过去了
He's out.
等等 我们到底要进入谁的潜意识
Wait,whose subconscious are we going into exactly?
小Fischer的
We're going into Fischer's.
不过我告诉他 是进入Browning的
But I told him it was Browning's,
所以他会帮我们
so he can be a part of our team.
侵入自己的潜意识
He's gonna help us break into his own subconscious.
没错
That's right.
防御者会追着你死缠烂打
The security's gonna run you down,huh?
看本少爷如何让让他们疲于奔命吧
Then I will lead them on a merry chase.
穿越之前一定要回来
Just be back before the kick.
好好睡吧 Eames
Go to sleep,Mr. Eames.
你没事吧
Are you good?
-喂 准备好了吗  -没事 我准备好了
- Hey! Are you ready? - Yes,yes,I'm... I'm fine. I'm ready.
Cobb 那里面会有什么
Cobb. cobb? What's down there?
我们想要小Fischer了解的真相
Hopefully the truth we want Fischer to learn.
我是指你的潜意识
I mean,what's down there for you?
（Arthur一直在第二层的酒店里活跃）
（Yusuf一直在第一层开车 ）
哈 看到了吗
Huh... did you see that?
（第三层做梦者 Eames）
Eames 这是你的梦境
Eames,this is your dream.
我要你引开医院里的警卫 明白吗
I need you to draw the security away from the complex. Do you understand?
-那谁带小Fischer进去  -我不行
- Who will guide Fischer in? - Not me.
要是我知道了路线 我们就完蛋了
If I know the route,everything could be compromised.
-这是我设计的迷宫  -不 你得跟着我
- I... I designed the place. - No,you're with me.
-我来吧  -好吧
- I can do it. - Alright.
你跟斋藤说一下怎么过去
You brief him on the route into the complex.
小Fischer 你跟着他走
Fischer,you'll be going with him.
好的 那你呢
Alright. What about you?
无线电不要关 我会一直监听的
Keep this live. I'll be listening in the whole time.
建筑上层的窗户都很宽敞
The windows on that upper floor're big
我可以在南面的塔楼上掩护你
enough for me to cover you from that south tower.
-看见了吗  -看到了  你不进来吗
- You see it? - Yeah. you're not coming in?
要了解关于你父亲的真相
In order to find out the truth about your father,
你要靠自己的力量 潜入Browning的潜意识
you're gonna need to break into Browning's mind on your own.
来吧  小Fischer
Come,Fischer!
拉警报 拉警报
Sound the alarm! Sound the alarm!
行动
Move!
快上
Go!
（第一层的Yusuf给第二层的Arthur带上音乐）
但愿你们准备好了
Hope you're ready.
不不 这太早了
No,it's too soon.
Coob 听到了吗
Cobb,do you hear that?
二十分钟前就听到了 我还以为是风声
First heard it about twenty minutes ago. I thought it was the wind up here.
我听到了 的确是音乐
Yeah,I hear it. It's music.
-那怎么办  -抓紧时间
- So what do we do? - Move fast!
Yusuf还有十秒就要跳了
Yusuf's ten seconds for the jump,
Arthur还有三分钟
which gives Arthur three minutes.
-我们呢  -六十分钟
- Which gives us what? - Sixty minutes.
一小时内 他们能赶到那吗
Can they make that route in under an hour?
不行 肯定到不了
They still have to climb down to the middle terrace.
重新给他们找一条路 找条捷径
Well,then they need a new route,a more direct route.
在那
There!
我是照迷宫设计的
It's designed as a labyrinth.
就算迷宫里也能抄近道吧
There must be access routes that cut through the maze,right?
Eames
Eames.
-Eames改过设计吗  -我不能告诉你
- Did Eames add any features? - I don't think I should tell you.
-万一Mal知道了...  -管不了那么多了
- If Mal finds out... - We don't have time for this.
他到底改过没
Did he add any?
他加了一条穿过迷宫的通风系统
He added an airduct system that can cut through the maze.
好极了 告诉他们
Good,explain it to them.
-斋藤  -说
- Saito? - Go ahead?
（做梦者可以用自己的意识影响梦境）
（第一层Yusef尿急导致下大雨 第二层Arthur改造楼梯 第三层Eames打通排气管）
-矛盾建筑  -不
- Paradox. - No...!
-怎么回事  -穿越
- What was that? - The kick.
-Cobb 我们是不是错过了  -对 是错过了
- Cobb! Cobb,did we miss it? - Yeah,we missed it.
雪山梦 丫的就不能做个海滩梦吗
Couldn't someone have dreamt up a goddamned beach,huh?
-这可怎么办  -在下次穿越前完成任务
- What the hell do we do now? - We finish the job before the next kick.
-哪还有穿越了  -车子碰到水面的瞬间
- What next kick? - When the van hits the water.
如需拨打电话 请挂机后重试
If you want to make a call,please hang up and try again.
没有重力 怎么让你们穿越
How can I drop you without gravity?
Arthur还有几分钟 我们还有二十多分钟
Arthur has a couple of minutes,we have about twenty.
你还行吗
Are you okey?
快走 回基地
Move on! To the base!
有点不对劲  警卫好像发现了什么
There's something wrong,they're heading your way,
朝你们那边去了
like they know something.
尽量拖住他们 能做到吗 咱们走
Just buy us some more time,alright? Come on!
这就去
On my way.
那就是通往保险库的前厅
That's the antechamber outside the strong room.
保险库有窗户吗
Does the strong room have windows?
要是有就不保险了
Well,I mean it wouldn't be very strong if it did.
但愿小Fischer喜欢我们的设计
Let's hope Fischer likes what he finds in there.
-那些防御者真的只是他的潜意识 -对
- Are those projections part of his subconscious? - Yes.
-他的大脑会受到损害吗  -不会
- Are you destroying those parts of his mind? - No,no.
他们都是想象出来的
They're just projections.
好了 我们到了
Okey. We are here.
你们那边暂时安全 大队人马正在往回赶 抓紧时间
You are clear but hurry. There's an entire army heading your way.
进来了
We're in.
看这里
Look here!
-里面怎么还有人  -小Fischer 有埋伏 快出来
- Someone else's in there. - Fischer,it's a trap. Get out!
快啊 再下来点
Come on,a little lower.
Cobb 不是 她...
Cobb. No,she...
-她不是真的  -你怎么知道
- She is not real. - How do you know that?
她只是个潜意识 小Fischer才是真的
She is just a projection. Fischer... Fischer is real.
你好
Hello.
Eames 快去前厅
Eames! Eames! Get to the antechamber now!
-怎么回事  - Mal把小Fischer杀了吗
- What happened? - Mal killed Fischer?
我的错 我下不了手
I couldn't shoot her.
不用救他了 他已经陷入潜意识边缘了
There's no use in reviving him,his mind's already trapped down there.
-游戏结束  -我们就这样玩完了
- It's all over. - So that's it? Then we failed?
完了 抱歉
We're done. I'm sorry.
这想回家的又不是我 对吧
Well,it's not me who doesn't get back to my family,is it?
好可惜噢 其实我很想知道结局
It's a shame. I really wanted to know what's gonna happen in there.
我觉得会成功的
I swear we had this one.
装炸药吧
Let's set the charges.
等等 其实还有个方法
No,there's still another way.
-我们跟着小Fischer一起下去  -时间不够了
- We just have to follow Fischer down there. - Not enough time.
错 进入下一层就有足够时间
No,but there will... there will be enough time down there.
我们会找到他的
And we will find him,okey?
当Arthur开始放音乐时
As soon as Arthur's music kicks in,
再用心脏起搏器救活他
just use the defibrillator to revive him.
然后在下面一层穿越回来
We can give him his... his own kick down below.
你把他抬进去
Look,you get him in there.
音乐一结束 你就炸掉医院
As soon as the music ends,you blow up the hospital,
这样我们就可以一起穿越回去了
and we all ride the kick back up the layers.
值得一试
That's worth a shot.
可我布置炸药时 需要斋藤掩护
Saito can hold the guards out,while I set the charges.
斋藤活不了多久了
Saito will never make it,will he?
-Cobb 总得试试啊  -试试吧
- Cobb,come on. We've got to try this. - Go for it.
不过穿越之前你们回不来 就不等你们了
If you are not back for the kick,I will go with or without you.
她说得对 行动吧
She's right. She's right. Let's go.
知道下去后该怎么做吗
Can I trust you to do what needs to happen here?
我是说 Mal也会在下面
I mean,Mal's gonna be down there.
我知道去哪找她 小Fischer肯定在她手里
I know where to find her. She'll have Fischer.
-你怎么知道  -因为...
- How do you know? - Because...
她想让我去下面找她
She wants me to come after her,
这样我们就能在一起了
she wants me back down there with her.
（Eames在第三层炸医院）
还行吗你
Are you alright?
-你们的世界  -曾经是 她肯定在这
- This is your world? - Was. This is where she'll be.
走吧
Come on.
来 哥们
Come here.
斋藤 斋藤
Saito,Saito!
帮我个忙 我布置炸药的时候
I need you,I need you to take care of Fischer,
帮我照顾好小Fischer 好吗
while I go set some charges. Okey?
这种工作 带游客可不行
No room for tourists on this job.
我收回
Who said?
这些都你们造的 太不可思议了
You built all this? This is incredible.
我们造了许多年
We built it for years.
然后按照记忆重建
And we started it on the memories.
跟我来
This way.
紧急制动
这是我们住的街区
This is our neighborhood,
都是根据记忆重建的
The place is from our past.
那是我们的第一间公寓
That was our first apartment.
后来搬到那面去了 Mal怀孕后
And we moved to that building right there,after Mal became pregnant,
我们住在那儿
that became my home.
这些都是根据记忆重建的吗
You reconstructed all of this from memory?
跟你说过 我们有的是时间
Like I told you,we had lots of time.
-那是什么  -Mal在那房子里长大
- What's that? - It's the house Mal grew up in.
-她会在里面吗  -不
- Will she be in there? - No.
来吧
Come on.
我们既可以别墅 又可以住高楼大厦
We both wanted to live in that house,but we loved this type of building.
可真实世界里 必须二选一
In the real world,we'd have to choose,but not here.
你准备怎么把小Fischer带回去
How would you bring Fischer back?
我们还是要想办法穿越
We have to come up with some kind of a kick.
-怎么穿越  -见机行事
- What? - We'd better improvise.
有些事情要告诉你 关于我 还有植入想法
Listen,there's something you should know about me,about inception.
一个想法就像病毒一样 顽强无比 感染性极强
An idea is like a virus,resilient,highly contagious.
再细微的念头也会生根发芽
A smallest seed of an idea can grow.
它能成就你 也能毁灭你
It can grow to define or destroy you.
一个很小的念头 比如"你的世界不是真的"
The smallest idea such as "your world is not real,"
非常简单却颠覆一切
Simple little thought that changes everything.
你是如此确信你的世界是真的
So certain of your world of what's real.
你觉得他分得清楚吗
Do you think he is?
还是觉得其实他也像我一样迷失了
What do you think he is as lost as I was?
我知道什么是真的 Mal
I know what's real,Mal.
一点疑惑都没有
No creeping doubts,
一点困然都没有吗  Dom
not feeling persecuted,Dom?
满世界都有匿名组织和警察追捕你
Chased around the globe by anonymous corporations and police forces?
就像盗梦者被防御者追杀一样
Or whether the projections persecute the dreamer?
承认吧
Admit it,
你早就不再相信所谓的现实了
you don't believe in one reality anymore.
留下吧 留在这里
So choose,choose to be here,
在这陪着我
Choose me.
你知道我为何而来 我想回到孩子身边
You know why I have the deal,have to get back to our children?
因为你抛弃了他们
Because you left them,
因为你离开了我们
because you left us.
-你错了  -我没有
- You're wrong! - I'm not wrong.
你还没搞清楚
You're confused.
我们的孩子在这里
Our children are here.
你也想再见见他们吧
And you'd like to see their faces again,wouldn't you?
是 不过我会回到现实的世界去见他们
Yes. But I want to see them up above,Mal.
现实世界
Up above?
你别犯傻了
Listen to yourself.
孩子们在这里呢
These are our children.
自己看
Watch.
James  Phillipa
James! Phillipa!
别这样 Mal 求你了
Don't do this,Mal. Please.
他们都不是真的
Those aren't my children.
你一直都这么说 但你确定吗
You keep telling yourself that,but you don't believe it.
-是 我确信  -万一你错了呢
- No,I know it! - What if you're wrong?
如果我这里才是真实的呢
What if I'm what's real?
你一直以为自己知道什么是真的
You keep telling yourself what you know.
那你告诉我
But what do you believe?
什么感觉是真的
What do you feel?
罪恶感
Guilt.
我很愧疚 Mal
I feel guilt,Mal.
不管我做在什么
No matter what I do,no...
无论有多绝望 多困惑 那种罪恶感...
no matter how hopeless I am,no matter how I confused,that guilt...
都与我如影随形 就是这种愧疚提醒什么是真的
is always there,reminding me of the truth.
什么真相
What truth?
你对真实世界的质疑
That the idea that caused you to question your reality
全是因我而生
came from me.
你把这个想法植入了我的意识了
You planted the idea in my mind?
她在说什么
What is she talking about?
我之所以确信植入想法是可能的  是因为...
The reason I knew inception was possible was because I...
我对试过了
I did it to her first.
-我拿我妻子做了实验  -为什么
- I did it to my own wife. - Why?
我们在这里困住了
We were lost in here.
我知道我们必须得逃出去 但她不愿意
I knew we needed to escape,but she wouldn't accept it.
她把内心的秘密锁在了潜意识最深处
She had locked something away,something.... something deep inside.
对于她曾经了解的现实  她选择将其遗忘
The truth that she had once known,but she chose to forget.
她深陷其中 无法自拔
She couldn't break free.
于是我决定去寻找它
So I decided to search for it,
走进她内心最深处 找到那秘密的角落
going deep into the recess of her mind and found that secret place.
我闯了进去
I broke in.
并且植入了一个想法
Then I planted an idea,
一个非常简单却能颠覆一切的想法
a simple little idea that would change everything.
"她的世界不是真的"
"That "her world wasn't real."
"只有死亡是唯一的解脱"
"the death was the only escape."
你在等一趟火车
You're waiting for a train,
它会把你带去远方
The train that'll take you far away.
你了然心之所向
You know where you hope this train will take you,
却不知自己火车开向何方
But you can't know for sure.
但这并不重要
But it doesn't matter.
告诉我为什么
Now tell me why!
因为我们会在一起
Because we'll be together!
但我万万想到
But I never knew that...
那个想法就像癌细胞一样扩散
that idea would grow in her mind like a cancer,
扩散到她清醒的意识里
that even after she woke up.
甚至扩散到了你真实的生活里
That even after you came back to reality.
你还是不相信 你活在真实的世界里
That you continue to believe your world wasn't real.
死亡是唯一的解脱
That death was the only escape.
Mal 不要 老天爷啊……
Mal! No! Jesus...
-你侵入了我的意识  -我是想救你
- You infected my mind? - I was trying to save you.
你背叛了我
You betrayed me.
但你仍可以补救 继续遵守你的诺言
But you can make amends,you can still keep your promise.
我们还是能在一起
We can still be together,
在这里 这个我们一起创造的世界里
right here,in the world we built together.
（第二层的Arthur给第三层的Eames带上音乐）
Cobb 我们必须找到小Fischer
Cobb,we need to get Fischer.
你们找不到他的
You can't have him.
-如果我留在这 能放了他吗  -你说什么
- If I stay here,would you let them go? - What're you talking about?
小Fischer在门廊上
Fischer's on the porch.
-看他还是否活着  -Cobb 你不能这样
- Go check if he's alive. - Cobb,you can't do this.
快去看看他是不是还活着 快
Go check if he's alive,right now. Do it.
Cobb 他在这  时间到了 你该出来了
Cobb,he's here. And it's time. You have to come now!
帮我把Fischer 带回去 好吗
Take Fischer with you,alright?
你不能留在这陪她
{\a2You can't stay here to be with her.
我不会 但斋藤已经死了 他肯定在这了
I'm not. Saito's dead by now,that means he's down here somewhere.
我必须找到他
It means I have to find him.
我不会在这陪她的  因为她不是真的
I can't stay with her anymore,because she doesn't exist.
对你来说 只有我才是真的
I'm the only thing you do believe in anymore.
是啊 我也想...
No. I wish...
如果是真的该有多好 但是...
I wish more than anything,but...
我想像不出你所有的复杂情绪
I can't imagine you with all your complexity,
所有的完美与不完美
all your perfection,all your imperfection.
你还好吗
You alright?
看看你自己
Look at you,
你只是个幻影
you're just a shade.
我真正妻子的影子
You're just the shade of my real wife.
我已经竭尽全力来想象了 可是
You're the best that I could do,but...
对不起 你远远比不上真实的她
I'm sorry,you are just not good enough.
这样感觉够真实了吧
Doesn't this feel real?
-你干什么  -见机行事
- What're you doing? - Improvise.
不 不 等等
No,no! No!
快进去 快 快 快
Get in there,now. Go! Go,go,go!
（利用 第一层套出的遗言）
（其实这里还是小F一个人的内心对话）
小Fischer
Robert?
失...失
Dis... disap...
-我很失...失... -我明白  爸爸
- I was disa... disa... - I know,dad.
我没变的像你一样 你很失望
I know you were disappointed,I couldn't be you.
不 不 不
No,no,no.
我很失望是因为...
I was disappointed...
你想成为另一个我
That you tried.
什么
What?
（528 491）
开启
遗嘱
（小F终于找到父爱了 植入成功）
该穿越了 Ariadne 快
That's the kick,Ariadne! You have to go now!
别迷失了自己 找到斋藤 把他带回来
Don't lose yourself! Find Saito and bring him back!
我会的
I will!
记得你向我求婚时说的话吗
Do you remember when you asked me to marry you?
记得
Yes.
你说你梦到我们一起慢慢变老
You said you dreamt that we grow old together.
是的 我们的确
But we did.
一起慢慢变老 你不记得了吗
We did,you don't remember?
我想你想到无法呼吸
I miss you more than I can bear,but...
我们厮守了一生
we had our time together.
现在我必须放手了
I have to let you go.
放手让你安息
我很抱歉 小Fischer
I'm sorry,Robert.
爸爸是想通过遗嘱告诉我 要我走自己的路
You know,the will means that dad wanted me to be my own man.
而不是为他而活
Not just to live for him.
我自己也是这么想的 Peter叔叔
That's what I'm gonna do,uncle Peter.
-怎么回事  - Cobb留在那了
- What happened? - Cobb stayed.
-为了Mal  -不 为了找到斋藤
- With Mal? - No,to find Saito.
他回不来了
He'll be lost.
不 他会回来
No,he'll be alright.
你是来杀我的吗
Have you come to kill me?
我一直在等一个人
I'm waiting for someone,
一个你曾经梦见过的人
someone from a half remembered dream.
Cobb
Cobb?
怎么可能
Impossible.
我们年龄差不多的
We were young men together.
而已经年华逝去
I'm an old man.
在悔恨中度过余生
Filled with regret.
孤零零地等死
Waiting to die alone,huh?
我回来找你了
I've come back for you,
是为了提醒你...
to remind you...
一些事...
of something...
一些你曾了解的事情
something you once knew.
这个世界不是真的
That this world is not real.
你是想提醒我要履行我们之间的协议
To convince me to honor our arrangement.
是的 放手一搏
To take a leap of faith,yes.
回去吧
Come back,
这样我们又能重回年轻
so we can be young men together again.
跟我回去吧
Come back with me.
走吧
Come back.
先生 热毛巾要吗
Hot towel,sir?
大概二十分钟后 我们会抵达达洛杉矶
We will be landing in Los Angeles in about twenty minutes.
入境登记表要吗
Do you need immigration forms?
谢谢
Thank you.
-先生 要热毛巾吗  -不了
- Hot towel,sir? - Oh,no.
入境登记表呢
Do you need immigration forms?
欢迎回家 Cobb先生
Welcome home,Mr. Cobb.
谢谢你
Thank you,sir.
欢迎回家
Welcome home.
这边
This way.
James Philippa
James? Philippa?
瞧瞧谁回来了
Look who's here.
-爸爸 爸爸  -孩子们 你们还好吗
- Daddy! Daddy! - Hey,kids! How are you?
-快来看 看我搭了什么  -你们玩什么呢
- Look what I built? - What're you doing there?
-我们悬崖上搭了所好大的房子那人  -用石头搭的吗
- I built a house on the cliff. - Out of rocks?